<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Hervey Allen papers, 1831-1965</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <titleInfo type="alternative">
    <title>Papers of Hervey Allen, 1831-1965</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <name type="personal" usage="primary">
    <namePart>Allen, Hervey</namePart>
    <namePart type="date">1889-1949</namePart>
  </name>
  <typeOfResource collection="yes" manuscript="yes">mixed material</typeOfResource>
  <genre authority="aat">Correspondence.</genre>
  <genre authority="aat">Family papers.</genre>
  <genre authority="aat">Financial records.</genre>
  <genre authority="aat">Manuscripts for publication.</genre>
  <genre authority="aat">Personal papers.</genre>
  <originInfo>
    <place>
      <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">xx</placeTerm>
    </place>
    <dateOther>1831-1965.</dateOther>
    <dateIssued encoding="marc" point="start">1831</dateIssued>
    <dateIssued encoding="marc" point="end">1965</dateIssued>
    <issuance>monographic</issuance>
  </originInfo>
  <language>
    <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
  </language>
  <physicalDescription>
    <extent unit="linear ft. manuscript boxes + oversized boxes).">90.0 (185 9</extent>
    <note type="arrangement">Organized into 10 series: I. Early Life, Education, Military and Academic Careers, 1890-1949; II. Manuscripts, 1900-1949; III. Published Material, 1919-1945; IV. Prose and Press About, 1920-1959; V. General Correspondence, 1903-1972; VI: Literary Correspondence, 1916-1956; VII: Projects, 1932-1949; VIII: Estates and Financial Matters, 1919-1952; IX: Family Papers, 1831-1965; X: Oversized Material, 1856-1953.</note>
  </physicalDescription>
  <abstract type="Scope and content">The Hervey Allen papers consist of handwritten, holograph and typewritten drafts and manuscripts, research notes, singular serial publications, and associated material related to press coverage of Allen's novels and film adaptations. Extensive personal and professional correspondence exists with Allen's main publishing company, Farrar and Rinehart/Rinehart Company, and other international publishers; financial and business correspondence related to his personal and professional finances; and personal correspondence with notable writers such as Stephen Vincent Benét, William Rose Bené́t, John Bennett, Carl Carmer, Padraic Colum, John Drinkwater, Robert Frost, DuBose Heyward, Amy Lowell, Kenneth Roberts, E.A. Robinson and Philip Wylie. Also present are the Allen's family papers which include correspondence, diaries, genealogical research, journals, newspaper clippings, photographs, and scrapbooks.</abstract>
  <accessCondition type="restriction on access">No restrictions.</accessCondition>
  <note type="preferred citation">Hervey Allen Papers, 1831-1965, SC.1952.01, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh.</note>
  <note type="acquisition">Portions of the papers were purchased from the estate of Hervey Allen (Mrs. Hervey Allen) in February 1952. Subsequent materials were donated through Holt, Rinehart and Winston publishing (formerly Farrar &amp; Rinehart and Rinehart &amp; Company) in 1964-1965 and Lawrence Kunetka of J &amp; S Graphics in 1969.</note>
  <note type="biographical/historical">Hervey Allen was born William Hervey Allen, Jr. in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, on December 8, 1889. Son of William Hervey Allen, Sr. and Helen Eby Meyers Allen, Hervey Allen was one of five children. Allen spent much of his childhood at his grandfather's home, Edgehill, reading from his extensive personal library. Allen was educated in Shady Side Academy and at Pittsburgh Public Schools, graduating from high school in 1906. In 1908 he went to Annapolis, Maryland, to attend Werntz, "a cramming school" to prepare for entrance to the United States Naval Academy. He was admitted in 1909 as a midshipman, but was discharged due to a stomach disorder in 1910. He returned to Pittsburgh and worked for the Bell Telephone Company. He then enrolled at the University of Pittsburgh's School of Economics in 1911, where he became a member of the Sigma Chi Fraternity. Allen graduated with Honors in 1915 with a Bachelor of Science in Economics. He joined the National Guard with the 18th Pennsylvania Infantry, earning the rank of 2nd Lieutenant in 1916. His regiment was ordered to the Mexican border near El Paso, Texas, by President Wilson during the Mexican Expedition, where he wrote and published his first collection of poetry, Ballads of the Border. Immediately upon his return, Allen was called to report to service for World War I on April 13, 1917. Allen was promoted to 1st Lieutenant of the 111th Infantry A.E.F. and spent the summer of 1917 guarding railroads in Western Pennsylvania. During the autumn of 1917, he went to Camp Hancock in Augusta, Georgia, for training with the 28th Pennsylvania Division. He deployed for France on April 30, 1918 aboard the Finland via New York. While at the front, Allen endured heavy fighting between the Marne and the Vasle. After the death of his captain at Fismette, he became Commander of Company B. He was seriously wounded there and was hospitalized on August 11, 1918. Upon his release, he served as an English instructor at the French Military Mission at Favernay. He was in Paris when the Armistice was signed. While at war, Hervey Allen wrote extensively and kept a diary of his experiences. From these writings Allen produced his most successful poem, The Blindman. His writings while at war inspired later works of his such as Toward the Flame and "It Was Like This: Two Stories of the Great War." By the spring of 1919, Allen had been honorably discharged at Cap Dix, New Jersey. He settled in Charleston, South Carolina, to teach English, History, and Military Drill at the Porter Military Academy. With the exception of attending a summer English course at Harvard University in 1921, Allen remained in South Carolina, teaching at Charleston High School until 1924. While in South Carolina, he was influential in the revival of southern poetry, founding the Poetry Society of South Carolina with DuBose Heyward and others. By 1921, Allen had published two major poetry collections, Wampum and Old Gold and Carolina Chansons, Legends of the Low Country, a joint publication with Heyward. Between 1924-1925, Allen was an English Instructor at Columbia University. By the latter half of 1925, Allen left Columbia to lecture American Literature at Vassar College. At Vassar, he met Annette Hyde Andrews, a student 18 years his junior whom he married in June 1927. During this time, Allen conducted extensive research on Edgar Allan Poe and published two separate works in 1926: Israfel: The Life and Times of Edgar Allan Poe and Poe's Brother: The Poems of William Henry Leonard Poe, a collaboration with Thomas Ollive Mabbott. Allen also published a collection of poems entitled, Earth Moods and Other Poems, and Toward the Flame, a novel based on his diary at war. From 1927 to 1932 Hervey and Ann Allen lived in Bermuda at Felicity Hall, a plantation in Somerset, Parish of Sandys. While in Bermuda, Allen published several poems and collections including Sarah Simon and New Legends both published in 1929. In May of that same year, he began to write Anthony Adverse, the massively successful historical novel set during the Napoleonic era telling a man's journey across several continents in search of meaning to his life. Allen left Bermuda to complete and publish the novel in the United States in 1933. Anthony Adverse became Allen's most successful book, topping the Bestseller list in 1933 and 1934. The novel sold over 3 million copies, was translated in 13 different languages, and became a motion picture produced by Warner Bros. and directed by Mervyn LeRoy. The film starred Fredric March, Olivia de Haviland and Claude Rains, and earned several Academy Award nominations including Best Picture. After the publication of Anthony Adverse, Allen devoted himself entirely to prose. The Allens settled at Bonfield, a plantation on the Eastern Shore of Maryland and remained there until the start of World War II. By 1938, Allen had written Action at Aquila, a historical novel about the Civil War and "It Was Like This: Two Stories of the Great War," in 1940. In 1943, following the death of Stephen Vincent Benét, Allen was appointed as co-editor to Farrar &amp; Rinehart's Rivers of America series. Together with Carl Carmer, Allen reviewed manuscript submissions dedicated to the history of individual American rivers. Also in 1943, Allen was appointed by President Roosevelt to join the War Manpower Commission as a Regional Information Representative in Atlanta, Georgia. Despite these commitments, Allen continued to write and set out to begin his most ambitious literary project: a five part volume on American history starting with Forest and the Fort, published in 1943, Bedford Village in 1944, and Toward the Morning in 1948. These three titles, though published individually, consisted of the first volume, The City and the Dawn, of the series, The Disinherited. Allen was working on Richfield Springs, the fourth and final installment of The City and the Dawn, when he suffered a fatal heart attack in The Glades, his Coconut Grove, Florida home on December 28th, 1949. He was survived by his wife Ann and their three children, Marcia, Mary Ann, and Richard. He is buried at Arlington National Cemetery.</note>
  <note xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="http://digital.library.pitt.edu/cgi-bin/f/findaid/findaid-idx?type=simple;c=ascead;view=text;subview=outline;didno=US-PPiU-sc195201">Finding aid Available in repository and on Internet; Folder level control; http://digital.library.pitt.edu/cgi-bin/f/findaid/findaid-idx?type=simple;c=ascead;view=text;subview=outline;didno=US-PPiU-sc195201</note>
  <subject>
    <geographicCode authority="marcgac">n-us---</geographicCode>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart>Alexander, John White</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1856-1915</namePart>
    </name>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart>Allen, Edward Jay</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1830-1915</namePart>
    </name>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart>Allen, Edward Jay</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1830-1915</namePart>
    </name>
    <genre>Diaries</genre>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart>Allen, Hervey</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1889-1949</namePart>
    </name>
    <topic>Alumni and alumnae</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart>Benét, Stephen Vincent</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1898-1943</namePart>
    </name>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart>Benét, William Rose</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1886-1950</namePart>
    </name>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart>Butcher, Fanny</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1888-1987</namePart>
    </name>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart>Farrar, John Chipman</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1896-1974</namePart>
    </name>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart>Frost, Robert</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1874-1963</namePart>
    </name>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart>Lowell, Amy</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1874-1925</namePart>
    </name>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart>Wyeth, Andrew</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1917-2009</namePart>
    </name>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart>Allen family</namePart>
    </name>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Bread Loaf School of English (Middlebury College).</namePart>
    </name>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Bread Loaf Writers' Conference of Middlebury College.</namePart>
    </name>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Farrar &amp; Rinehart.</namePart>
    </name>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Rinehart &amp; Company, Inc.</namePart>
    </name>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>St. John's College (Annapolis, Md.).</namePart>
    </name>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>United States.</namePart>
      <namePart>War Manpower Commission.</namePart>
    </name>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>University of Pittsburgh</namePart>
    </name>
    <topic>Alumni and alumnae</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <topic>Authors, American</topic>
    <temporal>20th century</temporal>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <topic>Authors, American</topic>
    <geographic>Pennsylvania</geographic>
    <geographic>Pittsburgh</geographic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <topic>Poets, American</topic>
    <temporal>20th century</temporal>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <topic>Poets, American</topic>
    <geographic>Pennsylvania</geographic>
    <geographic>Pittsburgh</geographic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <topic>World War, 1914-1918</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <geographic>Oregon National Historic Trail</geographic>
    <topic>History</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <geographic>United States</geographic>
    <topic>History</topic>
    <temporal>Civil War, 1861-1865</temporal>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <geographic>United States</geographic>
    <topic>History</topic>
    <temporal>Colonial period, ca. 1600-1775</temporal>
    <topic>Fiction</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <geographic>West (U.S.)</geographic>
    <topic>History</topic>
    <temporal>19th century</temporal>
  </subject>
  <name>
    <namePart>University of Pittsburgh</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text">depositor</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <location>
    <physicalLocation>University of Pittsburgh</physicalLocation>
  </location>
  <identifier type="oclc">ocn826915939</identifier>
  <identifier type="oclc">826915939</identifier>
  <relatedItem>
    <location>
      <url displayLabel="Finding aid">http://digital.library.pitt.edu/cgi-bin/f/findaid/findaid-idx?type=simple;c=ascead;view=text;subview=outline;didno=US-PPiU-sc195201</url>
    </location>
  </relatedItem>
  <recordInfo>
    <descriptionStandard>aacr</descriptionStandard>
    <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">PIT</recordContentSource>
    <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">130207</recordCreationDate>
    <recordChangeDate encoding="iso8601">20170109131947.0</recordChangeDate>
    <recordIdentifier>7233469</recordIdentifier>
    <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
  </recordInfo>
<identifier type="pitt">US-PPiU-sc195201</identifier></mods>
