
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 68: Lawrence Strike Cont&apos;d</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Politics and Legislation, Union Organization, Strikes</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon explains how the IWW helped organize the Lawrence, Mass strike which won workers higher wages and overtime pay and revived hope for the working people. Caption 1:  While the IWW, formed in 1905, never became the dominant labor organization in numbers, its free speech fights, its attempts to organize industrial unions won them the bitter hatred of employers and instilled new spirit among working people. When local authorities in a western town like Walla Walla, Wash. tried to suppress  organization among lumberjacks, the &quot;Wobblies&quot; poured in from everywhere to defend &quot;free speech.&quot;  Caption 2:  Jails were filled to overflowing until the authorities had to give up and free the prisoners. One of the most famous of the IWW organizing efforts was of the textile workers in Lawrence, Mass. in 1912. Thirty thousand workers had their wages cut by the American Woolen Co. These Italian, Polish, Lithuanian and Russian mill workers would earn less than $9 a week-if on a full week.  Caption 3:  Protests against this brutality swept the area and the country. Although 296 were arrested in the two months of the strike, the American Woolen Co. finally had to confess defeat. Wages were raised 5 to 25 percent, time and a quarter for overtime and other gains made. The strikers warned that unless Ettor and Giovannitti were freed they&apos;d strike again; 15,000 struck for 24 hours in protest. The two were found innocent. UE News, Volume XXXV, Issue No. 1</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1973-01-08</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.068</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.068</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
