
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 43: Immigration Wave</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Scabs, Businesses</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon depicts the rapid growth of immigrants during the 1880s.  These immigrants were used as cheap labor and as scabs. Caption 1:  The 1880&apos;s saw the tremendous development of machinery in American industry. Skilled handicraftsmen disappeared with the flood of inventions which averaged about 21,000 a year. One manufacturer boasted that he regarded his &quot;employees as I do a machine, to be used to my advantage, and when they are old and of no further use, I cast them in the streets.&quot;  Caption 2:  To man the rapidly expanding railroads and industry, the employers turned to immigrants. Between 1880-90 over 5.5 million arrived mainly from Russia, Italy, Hungary, Rumania, Germany and the Scandinavian countries. Company agents scoured Europe promising &quot;streets paved with gold.&quot; Others were picked off the piers in New York and shipped directly to steel mills, mines and textile mills.  Caption 3:  Many were brought in to scab on strikers who had revolted against miserable wages. Unable to speak English, the immigrants did not know to what they had been brought. When they learned the truth many rebelled. So did 500 Jewish immigrants who, brought to scab on N.Y. Central freight handlers, walked off a pier and to the union hall. A day later 250 Italians followed them. UE News, Vol. XXXIII, Issue No. 26</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1971-12-27</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.043</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.043</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
