
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 118: Electrical Workers Organize III</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Union Organization</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon depicts a UE constitution creating equal rights to all workers, no matter what age, gender, race or political stance. Caption 1:  The heart of the new industrial union in the electrical and radio industry was a constitution which established the right of every worker in the industry &quot;regardless of craft, age, sex, nationality, race or creed or political beliefs&quot; to belong to it. Possibly with the exception of age, there were unions which had discriminated against workers, or barred them from membership on every one of these grounds.  Caption 2:  Most unions of the American Federation of Labor organized only within a craft even when a large plant had a majority outside the craft. Consequently, most workers especially in the major industries remained unorganized or if there were more than one craft in a plant, each group was in a separate union, belonging to a separate international. Naturally, instead of unity there was disunity perpetuated by the unions themselves.  Caption 3:  Frequently, the craft unions barred workers who were not white or countenanced control of jobs by a single nationality through admitting only the sons of fathers in the trade. Accepting or even insisting on the employer limiting women to the lowest paid, least skilled operations also helped keep workers divided. And then there were unions which imposed political censorship on the members. The UE constitution smashed through all these divisions. UE News, Vol. XXXVII, Issue No. 3</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1975-02-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.118</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.118</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
