
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 153: Court Scores Blacklist</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Red Scare, Politics and Legislation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon depicts the opinions of several Supreme Court justices condemning the government&apos;s practices of espionage. Caption 1:  Right after the Emspak-Quinn acquittal by the Supreme Court, the court reversed the firing of Yale University Professor of Medicine Peters by the U.S. Public Health Service on &quot;disloyalty&quot; charges. His appeal against dismissal was upheld by the court. Justice Hugo Black criticized the government for conducting an &quot;espionage program over government employees&quot; and doubted that the President had the power to institute such a program.  Caption 2:  In a separate opinion, Justice Wm. O. Douglas condemned the use of &quot;faceless informers&quot; against government employees and employees &quot;who work for private firms having contracts with the government.&quot; Douglas declared that a man&apos;s right to work was a &quot;precious liberty&quot; protected by the Bill of Rights. These opinions helped undermine the blacklist policies corporations like GE, Westinghouse, Westinghouse Airbrake had been using to try to smash the UE.  Caption 3:  Some of the leading informers used by the corporations and the politicians began to expose themselves or were exposed as frauds. One of them, who had worked for Sen. McCarthy and the Justice Dept. even wrote a book confessing that his testimony against many people, including some in UE, had been perjured, bought and paid for. Other informers turned out to have been blackmailed into playing this role. UE News, Vol. XXXVIII, Issue No. 20</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1976-10-25</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.153</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.153</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
