
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 111: Sit-Down In Auto Plants IV</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Strikes, Businesses</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>The fourth cartoon in the Sit-Down In Auto Plants series. Talks between Michigan Governor Murphy and CIO president Lewis continued to go nowhere and tensions between the two were at a peak in February 1936. Caption 1:  Michigan Gov. Murphy came to the hotel room of CIO Pres. Lewis that midnight in February, 1937, to inform the union leader of his decision to use the National Guard to drive the sit-down strikers out of the GM plants. &quot;Law and order&quot; had to be upheld, the governor said. Lewis reminded Murphy that his father had defied British law and been imprisoned as an Irish revolutionist.  Caption 2:  &quot;When the British government hanged your grandfather as an Irish revolutionary you did not praise the glory and the purity of the law,&quot; Lewis pounded at the governor ... But now you do.&quot; The union leader then informed Murphy that his answer was &quot;no.&quot; He would not order the strikers out of the plants they had occupied. Besides, he himself would go into the Chevrolet Plant 4 next morning and direct them to disregard the law.  Caption 3:  Lewis continued to tell Murphy that he would move to an open window in the plant, remove his shirt and when &quot;you order your troops to fire, mine will be the first breast those bullets will strike. After you have had me shot,&quot; the union leader concluded, &quot;you listen to the voice of your grandfather as he whispers in your ear, &apos;Frank, are you sure you are doing the right thing.&apos; &quot; Gov. Murphy fled from Lewis&apos; hotel room. UE News, Vol. XXXVI, Issue No. 22</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1974-11-04</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.111</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.111</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
