
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 97: San Francisco General Strike</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Strikes, Union Organization</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon depicts how the AFL continued to ignore the unorganized working population and  made deals with employers until west coast shipping unions struck for inclusion and then a general strike of 127,000 swept the city in support of the strikers. Caption 1:  Many industries were unorganized for the most part in the 1930&apos;s. Among these were the steel, maritime, electrical, rubber and auto industries. The old AFL unions had no interest in organizing them as the bureaucrats at their head feared to lose control if too many members came in. They had their deals with employers, collected enough dues to support themselves in high style and lived the &quot;good life.&quot; Racketeering was common among such make-believe union leaders.  Caption 2:  For years the Intl. Longshoremen&apos;s Union was dominated by Pres. Joseph P. Ryan, notorious for his gangster associations. Tens of thousands of unorganized longshoremen started flocking into the union throughout California, Oregon and Washington ports in 1933. But they held on to rank and file control. The same was happening among West Coast seamen who were organizing into an independent union. When the employers refused to negotiate, both groups struck in May, 1934.  Caption 3:  The entire West Coast&apos;s shipping industry was halted by the strike of 35,000. Instigated by the Industrial Assn., San Francisco police launched an all-out war on the strikers. The press ran headlines such as &quot;Red Army Marching on City.&quot; Pres. Ryan came from New York to denounce the strike as a red plot. All of San Francisco labor rallied behind the strikers and a general strike of 127,000 swept the city. Tear gas and assaults by masses of police with guns drawn were common. UE News, Volume XXXVI, Issue No. 7</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1974-04-08</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.097</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.097</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
