
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 160: Westinghouse Rejects Bias Ban</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Businesses, Equal Pay</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon describes the battle between the UE and the Westinghouse company regarding the inclusion of a no-discrimination clause in their contract. Caption 1:  UE had made the incorporation of a no-discrimination clause in all its contracts a major demand at all negotiations. While much progress had been made by 1957, Westinghouse still resisted. Writing to the company that year to demand such a clause, Director of Organization Matles noted that 75 percent of UE&apos;s contracts already contained no-discrimination clauses.  Caption 2:  Again, the company refused. It admitted that in order to get government contracts it had to agree not to discriminate against workers. But the company stated that the government&apos;s representatives were &quot;reasonable&quot; when it came to enforcing equal rights while the UE would not be once it succeeded in getting such a clause into its Westinghouse contract.  Caption 3:  The UE demand received wide publicity and won the support of many noted people who wrote to the company on behalf of the union&apos;s demand. The following year, UE demanded an end to discrimination against married women by Westinghouse noting that when a woman had to take a temporary leave because of pregnancy she was fired and deprived of all seniority rights, regardless of length of service. UE News, Vol. XXXIX, Issue No. 3</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1977-02-07</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.160</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.160</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
