
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 144: Drive Against Liberty</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Politics and Legislation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon describes the pressures unionism went through from the Taft-Hartley act and from the media and press. Caption 1:  In hundreds of cities and towns, courageous working men and women had to withstand attacks by the press and radio challenging their Americanism because they insisted on the democratic right to belong to a union or peace or political organization of their choice. Children whose parents held firm to their rights were often the butt of cruel criticism by prejudiced teachers and misinformed schoolmates.  Caption 2:  There were clergymen who took prominent roles in this assault on workers&apos; rights. Some of the most active of these clergymen admitted years later that they had been wrong. Loyalty oaths became the fashion. School teachers, college professors, public employees, maritime, office and industrial workers were put under such oaths on threat of loss of jobs or even the possibility of being hired.  Caption 3:  With the Taft-Hartley law used to further fear, division and disorganization in the labor movement, the Brownell-Butler law to put unions under government license through a &quot;Subversive Activities Control Board,&quot; the Smith Act to go after non-conforming political groups, there was laid down the heaviest barrage against civil liberties ever witnessed in the U.S. In addition there were dozens of city, state and federal legislative &quot;investigations.&quot; UE News, Vol. XXXVIII, Issue No. 9</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1976-05-07</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.144</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.144</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
