
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 90: The Big Depression</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Union Organization, Economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon depicts how the workers&apos; suffering only intensified the longer the depression lasted and how they finally began to fight back with hunger marches and unemployment demonstration despite dwindling union membership. Caption 1:  For a dozen years unions had been helping employers promote profit-sharing and employee stock ownership schemes as substitutes for wage increases. These were wiped out by the crash. Company pension plans disappeared. The already weak union movement was crumbling. By 1933 there were fewer than 3 million organized, no more than in 1917. The AFL unions made no effort to fight unemployment.  Caption 2:  There were no accurate statistics on the number without jobs. Some said the figure was up to 14 million. The employer-dominated press wrote gleefully: &quot;Never has there been a period of depression so free from labor strife . . labor has shown its good citizenship . . . Labor deserves a salute.&quot; Willingness to starve seemed to be the main characteristic of the American worker.  Caption 3:  But when AFL Pres. William Green repeated his opposition to unemployment insurance, the Philadelphia Record wrote: &quot;Liberty to starve? Is that what Mr. Green asks for?&quot; The rank and file, however, was rejecting that advice. Hunger marches, unemployed demonstrations, refusal to permit evictions from homes, farmers&apos; refusal to allow bankers to oust them from their farms-a political storm was building up between 1929-1932. UE News, Volume XXXV, Issue No. 24</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1973-12-03</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.090</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.090</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
