
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 35: Panic of 1873 I</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Economy, Strikes</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon depicts how the Panic of 1873 affected the labor movement by forcing many workers into unemployment and employers to make wage cuts.  Workers responded by striking. Caption 1:  Growing labor unions after the Civil War helped boost living standards a great deal but suddenly, in 1873, the big banking firm of Jay Cooke and Co. collapsed and with it came down the whole economy. For the next six years the country was soaked in misery. It was estimated that a fifth of the workers were completely jobless in 1877 and only one fifth had regular full time jobs.  Caption 2:  In 1873 there were 30 national unions. Four years later only eight or nine were left. Hours of work were lengthened to 10 where the 8-hour day had been won. In 1874 about 90,000 homeless workers, two-fifths women, lived in New York City&apos;s police station houses, for the one or two days lodging permitted them each month. They slept on benches. This assistance to the unemployed the press branded as &quot;communistic&quot; as it sapped &quot;independence of character.&quot;  Caption 3:  Another paper, the New York World, said the answer was &quot;lower wages&quot; and the employers agreed. The answer was &quot;strike.&quot; In 1874 the Fall River, Mass. textile workers struck against a 10 percent wage cut. Employers rejected a proposal for arbitration as UnAmerican. The wage cut was taken back after one month. A few months later it was reintroduced. The militia was called out against them and after several months of strike the workers lost. UE News, Vol. XXXIII, Issue No. 17</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1971-08-23</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.035</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.035</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
