
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 114: Steel Workers Organize II</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Union Organization,  Businesses</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>After a union agreement was resolved with U.S Steel, other steel companies were disgruntled with this and used violence against protestors. Caption 1:  While U.S. Steel Corp. signed a union agreement with The Steel Workers Organizing Committee in 1937, the so-called &quot;Little Steel&quot; companies prepared to fight the new union. They stockpiled machine guns, rifles, tear gas, bombs. According to the LaFollette Committee of the Senate, the companies spent close to $44,000 for the munitions. In May of that year the munitions were put to use against 75,000 strikers.  Caption 2:  Armed company thugs and the police opened fire on steel workers at Youngstown, Massilon and Cleveland, Ohio. And people died. At least 17 were killed and the wounded went to more than 150. But the big battle came at South Chicago where a peaceful march of 300 Republic Steel strikers on Memorial Day were surprised by armed police. At the head of the parade were signs reading: &quot;Come on Out, Help Win the Strike,&quot; &quot;Republic vs. the People.&quot;  Caption 3:  The paraders were attacked and men and women fell before the firing guns. Tear gas grenades blinded those not yet hit and charging police came rushing in to complete the job with swinging nightsticks and baseball bats. The unarmed workers answered with stones before fleeing. There were ten dead to pick up and over 100 injured. About 20 police had been slightly injured. UE News, Vol. XXXVI, Issue No. 25</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1974-12-16</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.114</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.114</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
