
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 173: Labor&apos;s drive for peace</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>War</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon describes the reasons for protests against the Vietnam War and the beginning of labor unions protesting absent the war. Caption 1:  In 1964, Lyndon Johnson was elected President with the largest plurality any candidate for that office had ever received. His victory over Republican Barry Goldwater was based on the pledge that he would not extend American intervention in Vietnam while the Republican candidate called for even greater participation by U.S. forces. Johnson betrayed that pledge and hundreds of thousands of Americans were shipped into Indochina.  Caption 2:  Opposition to the war and to Johnson&apos;s refusal to end U.S. intervention grew so intense that by 1968 the President fearing defeat, decided against running for re-election. This time it was the Republican candidate, Richard Nixon, who promised to bring the war to an end while his opponent, Sen. Hubert Humphrey clung to the Johnson record. Nixon won but  gain the voters soon found that they had been tricked. Nixon secretly spread the war into Cambodia.  Caption 3:  This new betrayal raised the protests against the war to new heights. In June 1972, 985 representatives of trade unions met in St. Louis to protest the war and to plan their campaign against it. It was the largest national labor peace gathering ever held with 35 AFL-CIO and independent unions, including UE, from 32 states represented. They demanded immediate withdrawal from Indochina of every American soldier, gun, plane, warship and dollar. UE News, Vol. XXXIX, Issue No. 16</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1977-08-22</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.173</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.173</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
