
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 129: Women&apos;s Job Rights at Issue</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Equal Pay</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon describes UE&apos;s agreement that women would receive the same rate as the men who performed their jobs previously. Caption 1:  While many of the suggestions that came out of the labor movement&apos;s determination to help the anti-fascist coalition win the war dealt with converting industry to war production, some were of a different nature. The textile labor advisory committee, for example, proposed style changes which would save 100 million yards of fabric. These included elimination of women&apos;s three piece dress and suit combinations, shorter dresses, skirts and coats. Also, elimination of belts, pockets and flaps on slacks.  Caption 2:  In renewing the national contract with the Westinghouse company in 1942, the UE won agreement that women placed on jobs performed by men before the U.S. entry into the war would be paid the same rate of pay as men. Also, women were given a larger wage increase in order to reduce the differential between men and women that the corporation had long enforced. Here and in the contract signed with GE that year, the union gained maintenance of membership clauses.  Caption 3:  The UE&apos;s insistence on making the principle of equal pay for equal work a basic part of its collective bargaining program led to the National War Labor Board adopting that principle in ruling on cases before it. It was a case brought before it by the UE involving the Norma Hoffman Company that established equal pay for women as NWLB policy. This was then added to other contracts negotiated by the union. UE News, Vol. XXXVII, Issue No. 14</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1975-07-14</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.129</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.129</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
