
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 102: New Organization Starts</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Union Organization</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon describes the rapid growth of the CIO during its beginning. Caption 1:  The members of the ten-man Committee on Industrial Organization included the presidents of the Typographical, Hat, Oil, Mine, Ladies Garment, Textile and Amalgamated Clothing Workers. Some of these fell away when the going got rough; when they found that industrial organization could not be controlled the way their old bureaucratic set-ups were. The CIO started organizing unions where none existed.  Caption 2:  Opposed to the drive were men like Dan Tobin, president of the Teamsters, who called the workers in the mass-production industries &quot;rubbish;&quot; Matthew Woll of the Photoengravers who was also president of an anti-labor employer organization, the National Civic Federation and John Frey, of the AFL Metal Trades Dept. who had dedicated himself to stopping mass organization of labor.  Caption 3:  The new Committee for Industrial Organization aroused such enthusiasm among workers that millions streamed into the new unions. Hardly a year had passed and the CIO had passed the AFL in membership. At the end of 1937, the new group had 3,700,000 members; the old AFL 3,400,000. The AFL leaders had said these people could not be organized, were not worth organizing. UE News, Vol. XXXVI, Issue No. 12</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1974-06-17</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.102</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.102</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
