
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 130: Unity Abroad and at Home</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>War, Businesses</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon illustrates that during World War II, unions were focused upon backing anti-fascism while large corporations were taking advantage of the unions lack of focus and making large profits. Caption 1:  In the battlefields of World War II, the three major opponents of Hitler&apos;s Nazi armies were the United States, Great Britain and the Soviet Union. Domestically, the big industrial unions of the CIO, formed only a few years earlier, were a powerful force backing up the anti-fascist coalition. Heading that domestic power were the CIO&apos;s &quot;big three,&quot; the UE, Steelworkers and Auto Workers.  Caption 2:  But while these and other unions were doing all within their power to further quick victory over fascism, big industry was viewing the war as a grand opportunity to make a big profit killing. Between 1940 and 1945, corporate profits were four and a half times what they had been from 1934 through 1939. This was reflected in a 45 percent wartime cost-of-living increase.  Caption 3:  This increase in the cost-of-living came despite price controls. Black market operators developed ways of beating the controls. Manufacturers of clothing and other necessities got around controls by substituting inferior materials or changing the makeup of their products. The addition of a button to a shirt, for example, could be an excuse to  describe it as a different product entitled to a higher price. UE News, Vol. XXXVII, Issue No. 15</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1975-07-28</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.130</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.130</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
