
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 10: Two Cents an Hour</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Average Work Day, Politics and Legislation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon depicts the first declaration of the 10-hour day for government projects and the fight against this by private businesses.  Out of this, both employers and workers created labor newspapers. Caption 1:  Labor&apos;s movement for a shorter work day (shorter than 12 hours) in the 1840&apos;s had its first big victory with the declaration by Pres. Martin Van Buren setting a 10-hour day on all government projects. But private employers fought hard to stop the movement. New York leather curriers and dealers agreed not to hire anyone known to be a member of a society which would set &quot;the direction of terms or prices for which workmen shall engage themselves.&quot; Among the weapons workers developed then was the first labor press.  Caption 2:  Employers had been sponsoring papers which printed such propaganda as the &quot;Song of the Factory Girl&quot; in New England: &quot;Oh. sing me the song of the Factory Girl! So merry and glad and free! The bloom in her cheeks, of health how it speaks. Oh, happy a creature is she! She tends the loom, she watches the spindle, And cheerfully toileth away, And her bosom is very gay.&quot;  Caption 3:  To combat this kind of &quot;Works News&quot; girls working in New England mills started what is thought to be the first labor papers. In New Hampshire they set up in 1842, The Factory Girl. Then came the weekly Voice of Industry in Lowell, Mass. Writing to this paper a girl complained of working from 6 a.m. until 10 p.m. for $1.56 a week. &quot;Here am I, a healthy New England girl, quite well behaved, bestowing just half of all my hours, including Sundays, upon a company for less than 2 cents an hour.&quot; UE News, Vol. XXXII, Issue No. 17</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1970-08-24</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.010</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.010</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
