
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 120: Labor Supports New Deal</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Union Organization</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon describes the flourishing movement of protecting industrial unionism and the growth of unions during the 1930&apos;s. Caption 1:  How right the decision of the CIO unions, including UE, was in insisting on protecting industrial unionism was soon proven in life. Within four years the new movement had close to four million members. The enthusiasm generated by this movement, led in many instances by young people, carried over even into the AFL and into independent unions so that by 1940 the total number of  organized workers had tripled.   Caption 2:  Black workers, recent immigrants, women workers, young workers who didn&apos;t have the skills entitling them to craft union membership were added to the ranks of organized labor, especially in the CIO unions. There were 200,000 electrical workers now organized; 375,000 steel workers; 100,000  agricultural and packing workers; 400,000 automobile workers and the coal miners union soared to 600,000.  Caption 3:  Growing strong in industry, working people began thinking in terms of independent political action. Among the expressions of this was the American Labor Party in New  York, the Farmer-Labor Party in Minnesota, the Washington Commonwealth Federation on the West Coast. These movements gave powerful support to the New Deal program, prodded the politicians to move forward, supported the best of them and ran their own candidates. UE News, Vol. XXXVII, Issue No. 5</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1975-03-10</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.120</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.120</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
