
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 54: Convict Labor II</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Strikes, Scabs</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>Miners with guns would go to places in Tennessee where convict labor was being used and would free the convicts. Troops were brought in and leaders were convicted, which ended the movement, however convict labor came to an end shortly after. Caption 1:  Repeatedly, contingents of miners returned to areas where convicts were being employed in the Tennessee coal mines. Armed, some with masked faces, the miners would free the convicts and in some cases supply them with civilian clothes. Rewards for arrests of the union leaders went untaken as there was wide support for the workers.  Caption 2:  In August, 1892, 3,000 Tennessee and Kentucky miners assaulted a convict stockade at Oliver Springs, Tenn. They disarmed the militia and burned the stockade. Railroad workers refused to move a regiment of militia to the scene from  Chattanooga. Finally, troops armed with artillery came to attack the workers and drove them from the hills opposite Fort Anderson.  Caption 3:  Arrests, convictions of leaders to jail terms and use of troops finally broke the fight against convict mine labor. But such tremendous support had been gained by the United Mine Workers that when the state&apos;s contract to supply convicts to the Tennessee Coal, Iron and Railway Co. ran out in 1896, it was not renewed. It had taken 25 years to end the use of convict labor in Tennessee. UE News, Vol. XXXIV, Issue No. 11</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1972-05-29</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.054</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.054</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
