
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 59: Troops Kill Pullman Strikers</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Politics and Legislation, Strikes</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon details the legal lengths employers went to end the Pullman strike, the violence that resulted in the death and injury of workers and the Union&apos;s determination to keep the railroads shut. Caption 1:  A strike-strangling injunction was issued by a federal judge against the Pullman strikers. The company threatened not to rehire thousands of strikers. Railroad attorney Edwin Walker, appointed special government  attorney, wired Washington that the workers&apos; defiance of the injunction established a need for troops. On July 3, 1894 President Cleveland complied.  Caption 2:  Defying Illinois Gov. Altgeld who said: &quot;It is not the business of the soldiers to act as custodians or guards of private property,&quot; the President directed the forces stationed at Fort Sheridan to go to Chicago. The governor wired Cleveland his protest and said that there was no need for troops and that the newspapers had manufactured anti-labor hysteria.  Caption 3:  Newspapers called the strike &quot;A Revolution.&quot; They lied that hundreds of freight cars had been burned by the strikers. A typical headline was: &quot;Anarchists and Socialists Said to Be Planning the Destruction and Looting of the Treasury.&quot; The troops killed 25 workers, injured 60. Yet the American Railway Union kept three fourths of the railroads shut. UE News, Volume XXXIV, Issue No. 17</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1972-08-21</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.059</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.059</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
