
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 6: Labor Enters Politics</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Politics and Legislation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon depicts the varying successes and failures of workingmen&apos;s parties in New York and Massachusetts in the 1830s. Caption 1:  With conditions and wages getting worse, labor in the late 1820&apos;s put greater emphasis on political action. Workingmen formed their own local parties and gave heavy support to Andrew Jackson, the successful candidate for president in 1828. The new Whig party objected to &quot;throwing the polls open to every man that walks&quot; as it fought Jacksonian democracy. A  New York mechanics&apos; meeting formed a party after protesting against attempts to lengthen the 10-hour day.  Caption 2:  New York&apos;s workingmen&apos;s party ran its first candidates in 1829. Of 21,000 votes cast it drew 6,000. Newspapers had blasted the new party as the &quot;Infidel Ticket&quot;. Its women&apos;s leader, Frances Wright, was denounced as insane and atheistic. The election of carpenter Ebenezer Ford to the assembly was called a disgrace which would scare traders and investors from the city.  Caption 3:  Elsewhere, at Salina, N. Y., the Farmers and Mechanics&apos; Party swept the 1839 election. The Working Men&apos;s Party of Massachusetts gained control of ten towns in 1833. Labor&apos;s parties didn&apos;t last long, however. Some workers thought they should stick to trade unions. Others saw it more important to back the Jacksonian movement. Many were frightened away by the attacks on the parties as &quot;radical&quot;. UE News, Vol. XXXII, Issue No. 13</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1970-06-29</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.006</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.006</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
