
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 119: Disunity Proposal Rejected</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Union Organization</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon describes how the AFL wanted to return the newly created CIO to the ten original unions, however the CIO disagreed. Caption 1:  Although the Congress of Industrial Organization was having amazing success in organizing the millions of unorganized workers, its leaders proposed to meet with the leaders of the American Federation of Labor in the fall of 1937 to see whether the two organizations could be united. The AFL, however, proposed to destroy the CIO by having the ten original unions return to it and the newly formed ones such as the UE negotiate terms for admission.  Caption 2:  This would have meant dismemberment of the new industrial unions among the craft unions which had for so long refused to organize the &quot;riffraff,&quot; as some of them described the masses of industrial workers not in the skilled crafts. A series of conferences between leaders of both federations failed to resolve the differences. The CIO delegation insisted on the right of every one of its affiliates entering the AFL as a unit.  Caption 3:  Otherwise, UE for example, would have been cannibalized by a number of unions including the IBEW, the Polishers, the Moulders, the Pattern Makers, the Plumbers, the Steamfitters and the carpenters all of which claimed jurisdiction in the electrical and radio industry. Other of the new unions, there were 22 of them, would have become victims of the same divisive butchery. The AFL leaders&apos; proposal for disunity was rejected. UE News, Vol. XXXVII, Issue No. 4</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1975-02-24</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.119</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.119</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
