
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 66: The IWW Is Formed</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Union Organization, Politics and Legislation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon illustrates how unions like the Industrial Workers of the World were started to protect unskilled workers who were still denied membership to the AFL, and the general socialist sentiments of many of these groups. Caption 1:  Despite the growth of the big industrial trusts which employed large numbers of semi-skilled and unskilled workers, the AFL persisted in its philosophy of organizing only skilled crafts. These corporations were smashing strike after strike, in many cases with government support. Demands grew among workers for industrial organization based on militant defense of labor&apos;s rights.  Caption 2:  With the independent Western Federation of Miners as a cornerstone, the Industrial Workers of the World came into being in 1905. Metal miners, lumberjacks, migratory harvest workers, textile workers were among those who joined the IWW. Tough, uncompromising and overriding the prejudices which had limited the AFL&apos;s organizing activities, the IWW stirred the whole country. Socialist Eugene Debs, William D. Haywood of the Western Federation of Miners were among its founders. Haywood denounced the AFL as being the &quot;American Separation of Labor.&quot;  Caption 3:  He and others who led the IWW believed that labor must take over the means of production, the machinery, the factories. They called for a &quot;workers&apos; government&quot; to replace capitalism. Many songs, still sung by labor everywhere, grew out of the IWW battles which expressed their militancy. Typical was: 0! I like my boss He&apos;s a good friend of mine, And that&apos;s why I&apos;m starving Out on the picket line. UE News, Volume XXXIV, Issue No. 25</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1972-12-11</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.066</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.066</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
