
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 29: National Organization Starts</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Politics and Legislation, Average Work Day, Union Organization</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon depicts labor&apos;s movement to prevent bills from passing that would have jailed strikers for a year.  At the same time, employers cut wages drastically which prompted the call for a national organization. Caption 1:  The development of city trades&apos; assemblies during the Civil War gave labor the means of developing stronger political action. When the New York state legislature considered a bill to jail strikers for a year (1864), the N. Y. Trades&apos; Assembly held a big street meeting attended by 15,000. Speakers warned the legislators voting for the bill would be &quot;sent to hell&quot; in the next election.  Caption 2:  Similar gatherings and expressions in other cities helped defeat the bill just as labor action had licked an anti-strike bill in Massachusetts. But labor was not yet strong enough and employers were slashing wages. Massachusetts nail workers were cut 25%; Troy, N.Y. iron workers suffered a dollar a day wage cut. A national wage cut drive was now forcing a new action on labor.  Caption 3:  There was need for even greater strength and workers began thinking of national organizations. The Louisville, Ky. Trades&apos; Assembly issued a call for a national meeting of similar bodies. &quot;Are not capitalists and employers of almost every city organizing themselves into unions?&quot; the call asked. Although only eight central bodies sent delegates, the time was nearing when national organization would be established. UE News, Vol. XXXIII, Issue No. 11</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1971-05-31</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.029</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.029</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
