
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 170: Labor calls for war&apos;s end</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>War</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon depicts the labor unions beginning to speak out against the war. Caption 1:  Opposition to the Vietnam war grew as it stretched into the longest war in U.S. history and the casualty lists climbed. By mid-1967, the U.S. had suffered over 100,000 dead and wounded and there was no end in sight. Young people, those who were expected to do the fighting, were the first to speak out in an organized way. A 1965 March on Washington to End the War brought 25,000 young people to the capital. Administration spokesmen condemned them.  Caption 2:  Gradually, trade unions began to speak out against the war citing not only the casualties, American and Asian, but also the harmful effect the huge military expenditures were having on the economy. While the leadership of the AFL-CIO was giving unwavering support to the war, increasing numbers of rank and filers, local unions and leaders of some international unions, AFL-CIO affiliates and unaffiliated demanded an end to the war.  Caption 3:  The labor opposition was expressed in a Labor Leadership Assembly for Peace in Chicago in Nov. 1967 where over 500 trade unionists declared that labor &quot;must play its part in bringing this savage war to a swift and just conclusion.&quot; UE was well represented at this gathering which included vice presidents of 15 AFL-CIO international unions. Among the speakers were the Rev. Martin Luther King, Jr. and Rear Admiral Arnold True (ret.). UE News, Vol. XXXIX, Issue No. 13</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1977-07-11</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.170</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.170</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
