
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 31: Strike Wins 8-Hour Day</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Strikes, Businesses</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon depicts how workers used strikes to enforce the 8-hour day law as employers were reluctant to abide by it. Caption 1:  The Supreme Court ruled in 1868 that the government did not have to abide by the 8-hour day law passed two years earlier. Taking its fight to the states, labor in California secured 11,000 signatures to a petition for a state 8-hour day law. When this failed, unions announced in the press that as of a certain day their members would work no more than 8-hours daily.  Caption 2:  This tactic worked. The 1868 legislature voted an 8-hour day and labor paraded through the streets on Feb. 22 in a huge torchlight parade. New York passed a similar law as did other states. But most of these were ignored by the employers. So labor took to striking to enforce the law. 25,000, led by the miners, walked out in Pennsylvania.  Caption 3:  A New York parade in 1871, led by the printers&apos; union, had a sign: &quot;Peaceably if we can, forcibly if we must.&quot; The sign was mounted on a cannon! The next year 100,000 members of 10 unions struck and forced an 8-hour day agreement from the building employers. The victory parade drew from the N.Y. Times the query: &quot;what proportion of that long column of strikers &apos;were thoroughly American&apos;?&quot; UE News, Vol. XXXIII, Issue No. 13</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1971-06-28</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.031</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.031</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
