
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 172: Victory for democracy</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Politics and Legislation,  Businesses</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon depicts changes and dropping of policies that were used against the labor movement in the 1950&apos;s and on, such as the Subversive Activities Control Act, which made it illegal for a communist to work in a defense plant. Caption 1:  Fourteen years after it had adopted a policy of discharging any worker who relied on the Bill of Rights to protect him from persecution by congressional committees, the General Electric Co. informed the UE in December 1967 that it had dropped that policy. This after repeated demands by the union since 1953 that it do so had gone unheeded. Twenty-eight long-service employees, members of UE and other unions, had been fired under this policy including Local 506 Pres. John Nelson.  Caption 2:  UE Pres. Fitzgerald called on GE to amend the injustice  it had done those employees, not only destroying their livelihoods but also doing irreparable damage to them and their families in the communities in which they lived. The plea was ignored. The Cordiner policy, named after the GE president of the time, had played a major role in discouraging militant worker activity, in splitting the union and in weakening labor political action.  Caption 3:  Almost at the same time as the union learned of the GE revocation of its unconstitutional policy, the Supreme Court, in December 1967, threw out the provisions of the Subversive Activities Control Act which made it a crime for a communist to work in a defense plant. The court held that it would be &quot;ironic&quot; to sanction the subversion of the freedom of Association, a First Amendment right, in the name of national defense.   UE News, Vol. XXXIX, Issue No. 15</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1977-08-08</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.172</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.172</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
