
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 101: AFL Suspends 10 Unions</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Union Organization</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon explains the how the Congress for Industrial Organization was formed and the AFL&apos;s reaction to it. Caption 1:  A few weeks after John L. Lewis knocked Carpenters&apos; Union Pres. Hutcheson to the floor with a punch, the leaders of ten AFL unions met to form a Committee for Industrial Organization. They were disgusted with the AFL convention&apos;s decision to again postpone organization of the big mass production industries. And before Nov. 1935 was over, Lewis announced his resignation as vice president of the AFL.  Caption 2:  When the AFL Executive Council met in Jan. 1936, it had before it a demand for industrial union charters in the radio, steel, rubber and auto industries-all almost totally unorganized. The hidebound Council countered, instead with demands that the CIO disband on the ground that it was a dual organization promoting rebellion against the parent organization.  Caption 3:  When warnings to disband were treated with contempt by the ten members of the new committee, the Executive Council suspended those unions. When the AFL convention met at Tampa, Fla. in the fall, there were no delegates from the ten unions who were associated with the Committee for Industrial Organization. UE News, Vol. XXXVI, Issue No. 11</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1974-06-03</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.101</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.101</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
