
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 123: Organizing Despite Depression</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon describes the hardships of the unemployed and the increase in union membership during the Great Depression. Caption 1:  Seven years had elapsed since the outbreak of the worst economic crisis in U.S. history when UE and other CIO unions were bringing organization to millions of unorganized workers in 1936. Various government programs had created jobs for millions of unemployed on public works, in the building of homes, in creation of the Tennessee Valley Authority for public power and flood control.  Caption 2:  But large numbers of workers remained unemployed. For the employers this pool of unemployed was a weapon they used to depress the working conditions of those fortunate enough to have jobs. The employers and their organizations fought the government public works&apos; programs, said they were steps towards socialism, boondoggling operations and the workers employed on them just &quot;leaning on their shovels.&quot;  Caption 3:  Initially the heavy unemployment tended to discourage workers from joining unions but speedup and wage cuts made workers realize that they needed unions. In 1938 the UE organized 28 plants including GE plants, Allis Chalmers, Singer Sewing Machine, American Machine &amp;amp; Foundry, about 30,000 workers. At the first CIO convention that year, Pres. John L. Lewis cited the UE achievements, including the first national agreement with GE as evidence of CIO accomplishments. UE News, Vol. XXXVII, Issue No. 8</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1975-04-21</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.123</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.123</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
