
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 49: Early Fight for 8-Hour Day</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Average Work Day, Union Organization</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon depicts how the AFL and it&apos;s leader, Samuel Gompers, initiated a massive movement for the 8-hour work day all throughout the country.  Workers everywhere convened in mass meetings and demonstrated to show their support. Caption 1:  The newly-formed American Federation of Labor decided in 1888 to make the winning of the 8-hour day its prime aim. Pamphlets were to be printed, meetings held and the whole working people prepared for a general strike on May 1, 1890. Unorganized workers were called to set up Eight-Hour Leagues. A Slogan of the movement was: &quot;Eight hours for work, eight hours for rest, eight hours for what we will.&quot;  Caption 2:  On Washington&apos;s birthday, 1889, 240 mass meetings were held in as many cities which adopted 8-hour day resolutions. On July 4, 311 such meetings took place. On Labor Day the number had grown to 420. The AFL distributed over half a million circulars, 50,000 pamphlets. Pres. Samuel Gompers urged an International socialist meeting in Paris that year to mark May 1 as &quot;International Labor Day,&quot; the start of the 8-hour day.  Caption 3:  After further consideration it was decided to forego a general strike but to have the Carpenters start the fight with the backing of the rest of labor. On May 2, 1890 a New York daily headlined: &quot;Everywhere the Workmen Join in Demands for a Normal Day.&quot; Another headline: &quot;Parade of Jubilant Workingmen In All the Trade Centers of the Civilized World.&quot; Thirty thousand marched in Chicago; 70 unions were in the N. Y. demonstration. UE News, Vol. XXXIV, Issue No. 6</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1972-03-20</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.049</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.049</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
