
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 86: The Progressive Party</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Politics and Legislation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon depicts how the Progressive Party was formally endorsed by the AFL but the organization did little to help with the LaFollette-Wheeler campaign: the party won 5 million votes anyway. Caption 1:  The Progressive Party candidates favored public ownership of the country&apos;s water power, railroads, tax reduction on the lower incomes and abolition of the injunction in labor disputes. When both old parties refused to recognize labor&apos;s demands, the AF L reluctantly agreed to support the third party. The AFL had always, up until then, supported the two major parties.  Caption 2:  This time the executive council found that the two old parties had &quot;flouted the desires of labor&quot; are &quot;in a condition of moral bankruptcy which constitutes a menace and a peril to our country and its institutions.&quot; Many AFL leaders, however, supported the Republicans and backed the Republican Coolidge. Others backed the Wall Street lawyer John W. Davis.  Caption 3:  The AFL contributed a meager $25,000 to the LaFollette campaign. Outside of the formal endorsement, it did little to back the Progressive Party. Yet the new party, without any machinery, drew 5 million votes. As soon as the election was over, the AFL withdrew its support from the Conference for Progressive Political Action, which had launched the LaFollette-Wheeler candidacy.                                     UE News, Volume XXXV, Issue No. 20</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1973-10-08</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.086</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.086</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
