
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 1: The First Strike</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Strikes, Average Work Day</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon depicts the first strike in 1786 by the Philadelphia printers in response to low wages and long hours. Caption 1:  Relief from British oppression as a result of the American revolution did not bring relief from terribly long hours and equally short pay to American working men. Typical was the condition of New York workers who were paid 25 cents to 50 cents a day in 1789 for days running from &quot;sunup to sundown.&quot; Since they paid by the day, employers preferred to have their men work in the seasons when the days were longest and to lay them off at other times. &quot;Many of our small tradesmen, cartmen, day laborers and others dwell upon the borders of poverty,&quot; commented the Daily Advertiser at the time.  Caption 2:  There were strikes before there were unions as conditions became unbearable. Among the first to engage in strikes were the New York printers, who in 1778, demanded &quot;an addition of three dollars per week to our present small pittance.&quot; They won this without having to strike. But in 1786 their Philadelphia brothers made history with the first recorded strike for &quot;a dollar a day&quot; or six dollars a week. &quot;We will support such of our brethren,&quot; they resolved, &quot;as shall be thrown out of employment on account of their refusing to work for less than $6 a week.&quot; The &quot;turnout,&quot; as it was called, was successful.  Caption 3:  Philadelphia house carpenters lost a strike for a 10-hour day. Baltimore sailors and New York carpenters were among those who struck in the next few years. None of these resulted in permanent organization. Workers disbanded the organizations as soon as the battle for the immediate demand was over. In some cases workers tried to use their mutual aid societies as substitutes for unions as we know them. But when state legislatures passed laws forbidding this practice, unions were formed. Philadelphia shoemakers set up the first local craft union in 1792. It lasted one year. UE News, Vol. XXXII, Issue No. 8</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1970-04-20</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.001</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.001</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
