
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 171: War on poverty lost</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>War, Economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon describes the economic hardships that the U.S. went through in the late 1960&apos;s to early 1970&apos;s due to the cost of the Vietnam War. Caption 1:  When congress recessed in December 1967, it left behind the wreckage of President Johnson&apos;s &quot;Great Society&quot; program which had been proclaimed as the core for a &quot;war on poverty.&quot; Congress had voted the largest military budget in U.S. history, even surpassing World War II-$69.9 billion. For the &quot;model cities&quot; program which the President had pronounced as a basic pillar of his administration&apos;s policies, there was only $312 million. War on Vietnam&apos;s cities had replaced war on poverty at home.  Caption 2:  The military budget was laying the basis for the runaway inflation which was to persist into the 1970s. Corporate profits soared along with the war&apos;s casualty lists. As inflation pushed the cost of living up, the President called on labor to exercise &quot;wage restraints&quot; and proposed higher taxes to deprive workers of even more purchasing power in order to pay for the increasingly unpopular war.  Caption 3:  As the senate reconvened in January 1968, Democratic leader Mike Mansfield warned that because of U.S. expenditures in the war, American cities faced a national disaster,&quot; a prophecy that soon became a reality. Meanwhile, AFL-CIO Pres. Meany denounced the highly successful Labor Assembly for Peace as having been plotted in Hanoi. In the final days of the war, Meany stated that had he known earlier what he now knew, he would not have supported the war. UE News, Vol. XXXIX, Issue No. 14</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1977-07-25</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.171</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.171</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
