
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 16: First National Unions</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Union Organization, Economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon depicts the first formation of national unions in the 1850s until the depression of 1854 and crisis of 1877 broke them. Caption 1:  From the small local unions of the 1850&apos;s there began appearing the first national unions. Among these were the Typographical Union, Molders&apos; Union and Blacksmiths. They were craft unions as was all of the union movement. The organizations didn&apos;t last long as the 1854 depression and then the 1857 crisis broke them.  Caption 2:  The unions barred unskilled and a number of them including printers, waiters, shoemakers and tailors also excluded women. Some of the unions learned, however, that this did not help labor as when Cleveland tailors struck only to find employers hiring non-union women tailors to work at lower wages. The union then admitted women.  Caption 3:  Employers were also using the arrival of millions of European immigrants to divide labor. Propagandists blamed foreign born workers for lowering wages by saying they were willing to wear rags and &quot;feed upon the coarsest, cheapest and roughest fare.&quot; Employer agents would board ships to hire workers at $20 or $30 a year and board. UE News, Vol. XXXII, Issue No. 24</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1970-11-30</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.016</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.016</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
