
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 100: Rebellion at the AFL</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Union Organization</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon depicts increasing pressure on the AFL to organize industrial labor as well as their old craft unions. Caption 1:  The tremendously successful longshore-maritime strikes on the West Coast, was new proof that labor was ready for the biggest organizing drive ever seen. Although the Roosevelt Administration had enacted the National Recovery Act (NRA) which granted workers the right to bargain collectively, this had resulted mainly in a great increase in company unions and in AFL federal local unions.  Caption 2:  By 1935, however, over 600 of the federal locals had fallen apart. The Supreme Court, meanwhile, held NRA to be unconstitutional. Hourly wages in the electrical industry averaged 50 cents; a weekly pay check of $10 was common. The issue was squarely before the Oct. 1935 convention of the AFL in Atlantic City. On one side stood the big craft union moguls such as Hutcheson of the Carpenters, Pres. Green, Matthew Woll, and John Frey.  Caption 3:  The debate over whether the AFL should permit industrial organization raged with Mineworkers&apos; Pres. John L. Lewis demanding immediate action. With dramatic suddenness the frustrated Lewis strode to where the hidebound  &quot;Big&quot; Bill Hutcheson, 300 pounds of him, stood speaking, let go with his fist and connected. Hutcheson hit the floor. The fight made nationwide headlines. Industrial unionism was being born right there. UE News, Volume XXXVI, Issue No. 10</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1974-05-20</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.100</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.100</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
