
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 148: Labor Baiter Challenged</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Red Scare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon describes the uprisings of workers against McCarthy&apos;s attempt to destroy militant labor activity. Caption 1:  The country was in a severe recession in 1954, following the end of the Korean War. Well over 4 million were unemployed. As UE took the lead in developing a program for jobs, the big electrical manufacturing corporations worked closely with the infamous Sen. Joe McCarthy to drive out of the factories any semblance of militant labor activity. As GE officials sat in the audience, the Wisconsin senator badgered a group of Schenectady, N.Y., GE workers on their political beliefs.  Caption 2:  Pres. Fitzgerald called the senator &quot;a willing tool of the General Electric Co.,&quot; recalling that McCarthy had  previously done the same act at the Lynn, Mass. plant on the eve of a Labor Board election in order to prevent the UE from regaining collective bargaining rights. Thousands of Schenectady GE workers demonstrated against the McCarthy hearings and from all over the country came angry protests against the attacks on workers&apos; rights.  Caption 3:  When a black worker present at the hearings dared to clap at one point, McCarthy ordered two U.S. marshals to drag him to the witness stand. Instead of being cowed, the UE member, shouting above the gavel-pounding senator denounced &quot;your Ku Klux committee,&quot; and demanded to know why he didn&apos;t go after racist Senators Byrnes and Talmadge. &quot;They are the real UnAmericans. You are nothing but a bunch of fascist bums.&quot; UE News, Vol. XXXVIII, Issue No. 14</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1976-07-26</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.148</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.148</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
