
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 19: Lynn Shoemakers&apos; Strike - II</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Strikes, Scabs</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon depicts various issues regarding the Lynn Shoemakers&apos; Strike: including both women and men&apos;s fight for higher wages and the attempt employers made to use scabs. Caption 1:  From the 3,000 Lynn Shoemakers on strike, groups fanned out in 1860 to get support throughout New England. In a few days Mechanics&apos; Associations had been set up in 25 towns and about 20,000 shoeworkers in Mass., New Hampshire and Maine were out against $3-a-week wages. To the newspapers this was &quot;Revolution at the North.&quot; &quot;The Rebellion Among the Workmen, Beginning of the Conflict Between Capital and Labor.&quot;  Caption 2:  Weekly wages for women were as low as $1. They were compared to the &quot;amiable females&quot; of the French Revolution. Parading in Marblehead they carried such signs as &quot;American Ladies Will Not Be Slaves,&quot; &quot;Weak in Physical Strength But Strong in Moral Courage.&quot; Lynn employers persuaded the mayor to call out the light infantry and import Boston police. 800 people massed at the railroad station to denounce the invaders.  Caption 3:  Attempts to line up Germans and Irish to scab failed; so did appeals for Negro scabs. A Negro minister told his congregation: &quot;You, my colored brethren, know how to sympathize with labor unrequited.&quot; Many employers agreed to settle but not to recognize the union. Some strikers returned with a 10 percent raise and no contract. Others got signed agreements. After about six weeks the strike was called off and the basis laid for permanent organization. UE News, Vol. XXXIII, Issue No. 1</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1971-01-11</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.019</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.019</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
