
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 157: Merger of AFL and CIO</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Union Organization</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon depicts the merger of the Congress of Industrial Organizations and the American Federation of Labor in 1955. Caption 1:  Merger of the Congress of Industrial Organizations and the American Federation of Labor took place in Nov., 1955. Born in 1935 as the Committee of Industrial Organization within the AFL and becoming an independent Congress of Industrial Organizations the following year, the CIO affiliates succeeded in a few years to organize millions of unorganized workers while carrying on progressive political policies which earned it the hatred of big business.  Caption 2:  Following the end of World War II, the policies of the CIO became indistinguishable from those of the older federation. Its leaders insisted that all affiliates support the politicians they supported. They accepted the cold war policies of the Administration. They cut ten unions with one million members off from the organization, and sponsored raids and splits within unions which refused to accept their dictates.  Caption 3:  The CIO leadership even joined with employers in using the Taft-Hartley law as a weapon against the UE and other unions which refused to depart from the founding, militant policies of the CIO. Under these conditions, the CIO had stopped growing and its existence as an independent federation became meaningless. Many within the merged AFL-CIO as well as others outside predicted that there now be a new upsurge of labor. It never happened. UE News, Vol. XXXVIII, Issue No. 24</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1976-12-20</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.157</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.157</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
