
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 62: &quot;Divine Right&quot; Baer</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Strikes, Businesses</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon deals with the AFL&apos;s systematic exclusion of unskilled workers and immigrants and company owners&apos; refusal to recognize unions. Caption 1:  The loss of the Homestead steel and Pullman strikes encouraged those in the AFL who wanted to restrict the organization to craft unionism. Generally these were the same who were against admitting the unskilled Negroes and millions of immigrants arriving in the country at the end of the 19th century. The AFL leaders demanded that immigration be stopped. They said Italians, Poles, Russians, Rumanians, Slovaks could never be organized.  Caption 2:  These immigrants were denounced as being criminal types, willing to work for low wages, or as radical trouble-makers. One union which tried to unite instead of divide was the United Mine Workers, organized in 1890. Two years later, 150,000 miners answered a strike call in the eastern Pennsylvania anthracite mines. With a 10-hour day, frequent layoffs, their yearly earnings averaged $300. Fatal accidents were frequent, 441 being killed in 1901 alone.  Caption 3:  The united operators hired 3,000 &quot;coal and iron&quot; police and 1,000 special deputies to herd scabs. George F. Baer, the owners&apos; spokesman, declared that &quot;God in His infinite wisdom has given the control of the property interests&quot; to the mine owners and refused to deal with the union. As usual the press denounced the strike as an insurrection, Baer rejected Pres. Roosevelt&apos;s offer to start arbitration and rebuked the President for interfering. UE News, Volume XXXIV, Issue No. 21</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1972-10-16</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.062</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.062</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
