
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 103: Sit-In Strikes</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Strikes</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon describes how sit-ins became a new tactic for the labor movement to negotiate with employers during the 1930s. Caption 1:  The ten original unions which made up the Committee for Industrial Organization soon had new unions in the radio, rubber, glass, steel, auto industries. Instead of accepting this great historic fact, the old bureaucrats who ran the AFL launched an expulsion campaign. Every affiliate of the Industrial organizing committee was ordered expelled from city and state federations.  Caption 2:  By the end of 1937, the Committee for Industrial Organization had 37 affiliates. The AFL accused this new body of being communist controlled, a charge which some 12 years later, the CIO was to level at its own militant organizations in a later expulsion drive. The employers fought the CIO with slogans such as &quot;Join the CIO and Build a Soviet America.&quot; A pamphlet with that title was widely circulated by the NAM.   Caption 3:  The new labor movement gave birth to a brand new tactic--the sit-in. Faced by brutal police, militia and gangster assaults on picket lines, working people in a number of newly organized industries decided to stay inside the factories refusing to come out until the employers agreed to negotiate. It happened first at Firestone Tire Plant No.1, Akron, Ohio on Jan. 29, 1936 when the night shift at 2 a.m. pulled the switch. UE News, Vol. XXXVI, Issue No. 13</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1974-07-01</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.103</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.103</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
