
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 48: Knights Decline</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Union Organization</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon shows the decline of the Knights of Labor. Caption 1:  Although the Knights of Labor had grown to a big national federation of at least 700,000 members by the early 1880&apos;s, it had begun to decline when the Haymarket case took place. Its leader, Terence Powderly opposed the 8-hour day strikes and like the present head of the AFL-CIO, George Meany, boasted that he had never participated in a strike. Instead of striking, he advised members to write essays on the 8-hour day.  Caption 2:  The organization&apos;s funds were invested in cooperatives which were presented as the way to beat &quot;the system.&quot; The cooperatives were a failure. Strikes initiated by the members in different parts of the country were not supported by the Knights and most of them were lost. In two years&apos; time the membership dwindled to 200,000. By 1893 it had dropped to 75,000.  Caption 3:  An unsuccessful attempt was made to end rivalry between the Federation of Organized Trades and Labor Unions which had been formed in 1881 and the Knights. When this proved impossible, representatives of 25 labor organizations with a membership of 150,000 met at Columbus, Ohio in Dec., 1886 to form the American Federation of Labor with Samuel Gompers, a cigar maker union official, as president. UE News, Vol. XXXIV, Issue No. 5</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1972-03-06</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.048</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.048</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
