
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 33: Knights of Labor</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Union Organization</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon depicts the formation of the Noble and Holy Order of the Knights of Labor in 1869 by Philadelphia garment workers.  This union aimed to unite skilled and unskilled regardless of sex, creed, race, color, or political affiliation. Caption 1:                                                    Formed in 1868 the National Labor Union, first as a federation of labor, grew rapidly and then fell apart disappearing by 1872. Its leaders had lost faith in union action and had turned to various schemes such as currency reform and cooperatives as labors&apos; best hopes. Meanwhile another labor organization, the Knights of Labor, was coming into being.  Caption 2:  It was a group of Philadelphia garment workers who in 1869 formed the Noble and Holy Order of the Knights of Labor. Grips, passwords, rituals, secret symbols written on sidewalks and fences announcing meeting times and places were part of the Knights. Its leader was Uriah S. Stephens. Unlike most previous unions, he aimed to unite skilled and unskilled regardless of sex, creed, race, color or political affiliation.  Caption 3:  Through secrecy Stephens hoped to instill fraternity and solidarity in labor. The Knights grew to 700,000 members by 1886. In order to impel members to learn to read and write, each one had to sign his name to a card on a triangular table placed outside the meeting room. Many took courses in writing to be able to fulfill this requirement of membership. UE News, Vol. XXXIII, Issue No. 15</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1971-07-28</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.033</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.033</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
