
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 21: Labor Backs Lincoln -I</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Politics and Legislation, War</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon depicts labor&apos;s support for Lincoln in the 1860 election. Caption 1:  Working people were of many minds about slavery. Some feared competition of freed slaves. Others held that &quot;wage slavery&quot; should be the real concern. Avoidance of war at any cost was the desire of many. But in the years just  before the Civil War, the threat of slavery moving into free territory took top-most position. Economic competition of slaves and control of the government by slaveowners moved labor into the anti-slavery camp.  Caption 2:  Labor went for Lincoln in the 1860 election. He had come out for a &quot;system of labor...under which laborers can strike.&quot; He had recognized the truth that &quot;capital is the fruit of labor, and could not have existed if labor had not first existed...&quot; He was for assuring that slavery would not be spread to undermine free workers&apos; wages. Large numbers of foreign born workers were for him because he opposed bigotry.  Caption 3:  Secession of the southern states destroyed any lukewarm feelings about slavery that had existed among northern labor. Appeals for volunteers by Lincoln were answered in great numbers. Parades, mass meetings swept the country. Some unions dissolved as all members enlisted in the army. &quot;I having been resolved&quot; said one such, &quot;to enlist with Uncle Sam for the war, this union stands adjourned until either the Union is safe or we are whipped.&quot; UE News, Vol. XXXIII, Issue No. 3</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1971-02-08</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.021</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.021</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
