
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 121: UE Goals Reached</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Union Organization</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon describes the growth of UE as a union. Caption 1:  The very first UE convention, in March 1936, had laid out as union goals the organization of the General Electric plant at Schenectady, N. Y.; the Westinghouse plant at East Pittsburgh, Pa.; RCA at Camden, N. J. and the General Motors&apos; Frigidaire plant at Dayton, Ohio. These were monumental tasks, yet by 1940, the new industrial union had gone far beyond these goals.  Caption 2:  Some of the successes came only after bitter strikes such as at RCA and Emerson Electric in St. Louis. At the latter plant the workers went through a 55 day strike before the company would agree to a union contract. At GE, there had been a company practice of sponsoring company unions. Called Works Councils, these included management representatives.  Caption 3:  After the election of President Franklin D. Roosevelt the right of workers to form their own organizations was confirmed by the government. GE removed its representatives from the Schenectady company union and changed its name to Workers&apos; Council. UE supporters joined this group to help swing it towards real unionism. By the end of 1936, UE challenged the Workers&apos; Council in a Labor Board election and won. UE News, Vol. XXXVII, Issue No. 6</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1975-03-24</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.121</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.121</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
