
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 40: Chicago General Strike</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Strikes, Red Scare</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon depicts the Chicago General Strike in 1877 that developed out of the railroad strike in Pittsburgh.  The press labeled the strikers as communists and the strike ended violently with many killed and wounded. Caption 1:  From Pittsburgh the railroad strike spread on the Erie and New York Central railroads through New York, to Erie, Pa. on to Chicago and the west coast. The press was wild. The N.Y. Herald called the strikers &quot;a wild beast and needs to be shot down.&quot; The N.Y. World said Pittsburgh was &quot;in the hands of men dominated by the devilish spirit of communism.&quot; When the militia was called out in Buffalo, N.Y. a company of troops joined the strikers.  Caption 2:  By July 24, 1877, Michigan Central strikers in Chicago had been joined by most other workers in that city in what was almost a general strike. &quot;The City in Possession of Communists,&quot; the N.Y. Times headlined although all it was a fight against a wage cut. 20,000 strikers marched there with banners: &quot;We Want Work Not Charity,&quot; &quot;Why Does Overproduction Cause Starvation?&quot;  Caption 3:  Two days later the strikers were attacked by cavalrymen waving swords at the Halsey Street viaduct. Twelve were killed and many wounded. Federal troops were brought in from Indian territory. Strike headquarters were smashed; many workers&apos; leaders jailed. A few days of battling in the streets preceded the breaking of the Chicago strike. Between 30-50 had been killed and hundreds wounded. The trains moved again. UE News, Vol. XXXIII, Issue No. 23</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1971-11-15</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.040</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.040</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
