
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 65: Anti-Trust Laws Misused</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Politics and Legislation, Businesses</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon depicts big business control over government and misuse of legislation, like the Anti-Trust Act, to stamp down union rebellion. Caption 1:  The turning of the Sherman anti-trust act into a weapon to break strikes; the use of court injunctions for the same end aroused the labor movement to a new danger. Then, AFL Pres. Samuel Gompers was sentenced to a year in jail for advising workers to boycott products of a struck stove company. The AFL leader was shocked that even though he was trying to promote friendship for employers, and oppose independent political action, he was given treatment usually reserved for labor radicals.  Caption 2:  The Supreme Court overthrew the Gompers conviction but the AFL convention in 1906 appealed to Congress for exemption from the Sherman Act and relief from court injunctions. Ignored, Gompers asked the Democratic and Republican conventions two years later for support. It opposed Republican Presidential nominee, William Howard Taft because he was an injunction judge. It supported the Democrats although Gompers had always insisted labor should not take political sides.  Caption 3:  The assaults on labor, supported by government led to a drop in AFL members so that by 1910 there were fewer belonging than in 1904. Labor was facing a new situation-giant industrial trusts like U.S. Steel, International Harvester, General Electric. These were the creations of the bankers headed by J. P. Morgan. A handful of men were manipulating the country. With their huge wealth they became tough customers for labor. UE News, Volume XXXIV, Issue No. 24</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1972-11-27</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.065</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.065</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
