
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 11: Large Scale Immigration</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Average Work Day, Economy</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>In the mid 1800s, labor suffered setbacks due to increases in the use of machinery and large scale immigration.  Wages dropped dramatically, affecting the lives of many workers and immigrants. Caption 1:  Machinery was rapidly taking over from hand production in the 1840&apos;s. The shoemakers (Lynn, Mass.) who had their little shops in season and could dig clams out of season were being swallowed by factories; power looms displaced hand-loom weavers; power presses replaced hand printing. This was accompanied by severe earning slashes. Hatters pay, for example, dropped from $12 to $8 a week between 1835 and 1845.  Caption 2:  Millions of immigrants were arriving. Only one million had come in the first 50 years of the nation; from 1846 to 1855 about three million came. They were refugees from famines as in Ireland; from suppressed revolutions as in Germany. Employers took advantage of this to provide themselves with cheap labor. An 1850 budget said about $11 a week was the minimum needed for a N.Y. family. Average weekly earnings were $1 a person.  Caption 3:  Slums grew in this misery. N.Y. had 18,000 living in cellars; from 6 to 20 persons in a single room. A Boston study (1849) told of people &quot;huddled together like brutes...&quot; sometimes wife, husband, brothers and sisters in the same beds.&quot; A tremendous protest movement for a shorter work day, for decent living conditions was growing. Refugees from unsuccessful European revolutions responded eagerly to native leaders who sought to curb capital&apos;s greed. UE News, Vol. XXXII, Issue No. 18</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1970-09-07</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.011</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.011</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
