
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 134: Assaults on Strikers Protested</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Strikes</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon describes the national support for strikers during the labor movement.   Caption 1:  Ten thousand Philadelphia citizens assembled at the city hall to denounce the March 6, 1946 police attack on GE and Westinghouse strikers. They demanded that the mayor call off the police. From all over the country came wires and calls backing the right of strikers to exercise the right to free speech and assembly. In several New Jersey cities the companies got court injunctions.  Caption 2:  In Bloomfield, N.J., a British law dating back to King Edward III, almost 900 years ago, was used as the basis for an injunction which authorized the sheriff to &quot;kill, hurt and wound&quot; the Westinghouse strikers, almost all young women. The sheriff recruited nearly 200 toughs, armed with clubs and guns to terrorize the strikers. A company lawyer acted as prosecutor against arrested strikers.  Caption 3:  Support for the strikers was so widespread that even the courts were affected. So, those union leaders arrested in New Jersey were acquitted. Hundreds of workers had demonstrated outside the court house, headed by three UE members dressed to represent the &quot;Spirit of &apos;76&quot; of the American revolution. The GE strike was already in its ninth week when the company agreed to sit down and negotiate. UE News, Vol. XXXVII, Issue No. 24</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1975-12-01</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.134</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.134</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
