
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 8: Women&apos;s Union Strikes</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Strikes</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon depicts several strikes by women&apos;s unions in the 1830s. Caption 1:  Unions sprang UP all over the east coast and as far as St. Louis between 1833-37. More than 150 of them were set up in New York, Philadelphia, Boston. There were 168 strikes in that time. Of special note were the activities of the &quot;Ladies Unions.&quot; At Dover, N.H., 700 girls struck; at Lowell, Mass., a 15% wage cut led to 800 girls striking in 1834. They lost. Two years later wages were cut 12% and they were out again.  Caption 2:  Forming a factory girls assn., with 2,500 members, these Lowell workers marched through the streets singing: Oh, isn&apos;t it a pity that such a pretty girl as I, Should be sent to the factory to pine away and die? Oh! I cannot be a slave! I will not be a slave. For I&apos;m so fond of liberty, That I cannot be a slave.  Caption 3:  They were thrown out of the boarding houses, starved into surrender. Ordered to tend two looms, Amesbury girls stopped work and pledged &quot;under a forfeit of five dollars&quot; not to go back to work until the speed-up was dropped. They won. While some men objected to women&apos;s union activities, others held that &quot;unless we have the female sex on our side, we cannot hope to accomplish any object we have in view.&quot; UE News, Vol. XXXII, Issue No. 15</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1970-07-27</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.008</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.008</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
