
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 133: 1,500,000 Join Strike</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Strikes</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon describes a time period in 1946 where 1,500,000 workers went on strike. Caption 1:  As January, 1946 drew to an end, there were some 1,500,000 workers on strike in the United States. The day after UE struck 73 GE, Westinghouse and GM electrical division plants, the CIO Packinghouse Workers shut down the five biggest corporations in the meat industry. The CIO Communications Workers struck Western Union. Even independent unions as that of 17,000 Western Electric workers in New Jersey were drawn into the struggle to recover wage losses incurred during World War II and to make some long deferred gains.  Caption 2:  Six hundred war veterans on strike at Pennsylvania GE and Westinghouse plants marched on the governor&apos;s office to demand unemployment insurance. Gov. Martin fled rather than face the workers who occupied the House of  Representatives room for a meeting with other officials. A group of upstate Farmers Union members contributed a heifer to GE strikers. Made desperate by the complete paralysis of their plants, and getting nowhere with attempts to hire scabs, the companies turned to violence.   Caption 3:  One of the most brutal attacks on strikers occurred on March 6, 1946 in Philadelphia as police threw themselves on a meeting of GE and Westinghouse strikers. The strikers had assembled seven blocks from the GE plant to protest a court injunction the company had gotten to break the picket lines. Dozens were clubbed to the ground and workers who sought refuge on porches in the area were followed and beaten there. An entire neighborhood was roped off as the police sought to terrorize strike sympathizers. UE News, Vol. XXXVII, Issue No. 23</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1975-11-17</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.133</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.133</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
