
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 141: Labor&apos;s Ranks Divided</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Politics and Legislation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>This cartoon describes the anti-labor laws and policies and how they were upheld in the work force. Caption 1:  The UE and other unions which insisted on up-holding the founding principles of that organization were the subject of raids on their membership by sister unions even before the Taft-Hartley law was enacted. First those unions helped create the climate for passage of the anti-labor law by splitting the ranks of labor; then after denouncing the law they used it as a weapon to disorganize the organized.  Caption 2:  Mineworker Pres. John L. Lewis had said of those union leaders who agreed to live with the Taft-Hartley law that they were &quot;kneeling in obeisance,&quot; before a &quot;detestable and tyrannical statue.&quot; Now those leaders encouraged the anti-labor congressional committees to wage war on the democratic rights of working people. As the anti-labor propaganda poured out of committee rooms, corporations stood ready to further the divisions in labor&apos;s ranks.  Caption 3:  Corporations, such as GE, decreed that any worker who failed to satisfy the anti-labor politicians would be fired automatically. Union leaders who refused to abide by the Taft-Hartley law restrictions on labor&apos;s political independence  were cited for contempt of congress, subjected to violent denunciations by the press and in a number of instances sent to jail. Labor organization came to a halt. UE News, Vol. XXXVIII, Issue No. 6</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1976-03-22</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.141</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.141</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
