
<oai_dc:dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
  <dc:title>Labor History - 30: Eight Hour Day Movement</dc:title>
  <dc:creator>Fred Wright</dc:creator>
  <dc:subject>Economy, Average Work Day, Union Organization, Politics and Legislation</dc:subject>
  <dc:description>After the Civil War labor realized the need for national organization and formed the National Labor Union in 1866.  It&apos;s main goal was the 8-hour day, which President Andrew Johnson signed into law. Caption 1:  Union soldiers returning from the Civil War found unemployment facing them. There were growing demands for an eight-hour day instead of the 10 being worked. Labor saw the need for national organization. The answer was a national congress which formed the National Labor Union (1866-Baltimore). Of the 60,000 represented, many came from eight-hour day leagues and local unions.  Caption 2:  Organization of the unorganized, independent political action of labor and the eight-hour day were the key resolutions adopted. In the months following there were many successes. &quot;Seven workingmen or other good citizens,&quot; wrote an NLU organizer, &quot;who favor our views...can form a union.&quot; The Ohio chairman wrote of having set up 20 unions. By 1869 membership was set at 600,000 in the NLU.  Caption 3:  The 1866 meeting set up a committee to see President Andrew Johnson on the eight-hour day, on ending convict labor and keeping public lands out of the hands of speculators. Two years later the organization had proven its worth. Congress voted for an eight-hour day for all in government employ. It was 28 years since President Van Buren had ordered a 10-hour day for federal employees. UE News, Vol. XXXIII, Issue No. 12</dc:description>
  <dc:contributor>University of Pittsburgh (depositor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:contributor>James Lerner (contributor)</dc:contributor>
  <dc:date>1971-06-14</dc:date>
  <dc:type>StillImage</dc:type>
  <dc:type>Publication plate</dc:type>
  <dc:identifier>pitt:ue13.3.1.030</dc:identifier>
  <dc:identifier>pitt: ue13.3.1.030</dc:identifier>
  <dc:relation>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</dc:relation>
  <dc:rights>Copyright Not Evaluated. The copyright and related rights status of this Item has not been evaluated. Please refer to the organization that has made the Item available for more information. You are free to use this Item in any way that is permitted by the copyright and related rights legislation that applies to your use.</dc:rights>
  <dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
</oai_dc:dc>
