<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
  version="3.5"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Bob Johnson Papers 1949-2003</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <name type="personal" usage="primary">
    <namePart>Johnson, Robert</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text">creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <typeOfResource collection="yes" manuscript="yes">mixed material</typeOfResource>
  <genre authority="Art &amp; Architecture Thesaurus">Faculty papers</genre>
  <genre authority="Art &amp; Architecture Thesaurus">Personal papers</genre>
  <originInfo>
    <place>
      <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">xx</placeTerm>
    </place>
    <dateOther>1949-2003</dateOther>
    <issuance>monographic</issuance>
  </originInfo>
  <language>
    <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
  </language>
  <physicalDescription>
    <extent unit="(15 boxes)">17.0 linear feet</extent>
    <note type="arrangement">The Bob Johnson Papers are arranged into the following series: 

I. Personal Material, 1949-1992

II. Stephanie Johnson, ca. 1950- 2003

III. Journals/Notebooks, ca.1960-1986

IV. Artistic and Professional Career, 1956-1996

V. Pittsburgh Black Theatre Dance Ensemble, 1970-1985

VI. Teaching at the University of Pittsburgh, 1969-1986

VII. Black Arts Movement Scripts and Ephemera, 1966-1990</note>
  </physicalDescription>
  <abstract type="Summary">The Robert Johnson Papers date from Johnson's late teens and early twenties in 1950s and 1960s New York City through his death in Pittsburgh in 1986. The collection is comprised of personal and professional letters, writings, contracts, scripts, theatre ephemera, and choreographic and artistic notes/illustrations. Further, the Johnson Papers contain photographic and A/V items, press clippings, material related to the Pittsburgh Black Theatre Dance Ensemble, material related to his tenure as a lecturer at the University of Pittsburgh, and the papers of his widow, the late Stephanie Cooper Johnson.  The collection is broken into eight series and a number of subseries and sections.  For the most part, each subseries' or section's folders are listed in chronological order.</abstract>
  <abstract type="Summary">The Bob Johnson Papers contain paper based, photographic, and audio-visual materials related to the Brooklyn born, Pittsburgh based, dancer/choreographer, actor and director. Johnson founded the Pittsburgh Black Theatre Dance Ensemble and served as a dance and drama lecturer at the University of Pittsburgh.  Additionally, Robert Johnson toured internationally as a dancer and participated in a number of local, Broadway, and Off-Broadway productions as an actor, choreographer, and director.</abstract>
  <accessCondition type="restriction on access">In compliance with FERPA regulations, the following
    material has restricted access: Series VI: Teaching at the University of Pittsburgh: Subseries
    3: Classes: Section: Student Work. To access material in this series the researcher must agree
    to sign a confidentiality agreement provided by the Archives &amp; Special Collections. All
    remaining portions of the collection are free of restrictions. </accessCondition>
  <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">The University of Pittsburgh holds the property
    rights to the material in this collection, but the copyright may still be held by the original
    creator/author. Researchers are therefore advised to follow the regulations set forth in the
    U.S. Copyright Code when publishing, quoting, or reproducing material from this collection
    without the consent of the creator/author or that go beyond what is allowed by fair
    use.</accessCondition>
  <note>Processing Information: This collection was processed by Meaghan Alston and Catherine Peebles between September 2015 and August 2016. </note>
  <note type="preferred citation">Bob Johnson Papers, 1949-2003, CTC.2014.03, Curtis Theatre Collection, Archives &amp; Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System</note>
  <note type="acquisition">Gift of the Johnson Estate: Marimba Johnson Bright (daughter) and Samba Johnson (son) in December 2014. </note>
  <note type="biographical/historical">Robert “Bob” Johnson was born on March 31, 1938 in Brooklyn, New York to Viola Sutton and Fredrick Johnson. He received his foundational dance training at the New York Metropolitan High School of the Performing Arts (now LaGuardia High School of Music &amp; Art and Performing Arts). Johnson began his professional career in 1960 as a member of the Eleo Pomare and Raymond Sawyer Dance Company. During this time, he continued his formal study of dance at a number of New York based studios.  On scholarships, Johnson studied dance composition, Hattian and Afro-Caribbean under Jean-Léon Destiné at the New Dance Group Studio, the Lector Horton Technique at the Clark Center of the Performing Arts, and the Katherine Dunham Technique under Ms. Dunham herself.

In 1965, Johnson traveled to Paris as part of Katherine Dunham’s last professional company and took part in the French movie musical Deux Anges Sont Venus and the film adaptation of Léopold Sédar Senghor’sChaka. Upon returning to the United States in 1966, Mr. Johnson took dance instructor positions in Washington D.C. and New York City.  In this same year he made his acting debut as the lead in Kelly Marie Berry’s dance drama, Black Happenin’. In 1967, Bob Johnson appeared in the N.Y. Shakespeare Festival original production of Hair. This was quickly followed by a dramatic role in Ed Bullins’ Off-Broadway production,Goin’ a Buffallo. Between 1968 and 1969 he returned to his dance background with stints with the Harlem Cultural Council’s Dancemobile.

In 1969, Bob Johnson relocated to Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania to serve as a dance consultant for Project Self Esteem, a collaboration between local universities and youth groups. Members of the University of Pittsburgh’s Black Studies Department took notice of Johnson in this role and offered him a position teaching both dance and drama in the department starting in the 1970-1971 school year. He accepted the post and remained in the department until his death in 1986. His courses included Afro American Dance I and II and Kuumba Theatre Workshop, later renamed Creativity Workshop. It was also in Pittsburgh where he met and married his wife, the former Stephanie Cooper. 

In 1970, Bob Johnson founded the Pittsburgh Black Theatre Dance Ensemble which aimed to shed light on the breadth of culture in the African Diaspora to bring attention to issues facing the community through dance. Johnson served as artistic director of the company for a number of years during which time he choreographed signature works such as Free Spirit Song, Ritual of Damballah, Ego Trippin’ and American Fruit with African Roots. Outside of at the university and the dance company he founded Mr. Johnson continued to work professionally as a dancer, choreographer, actor and director. During the summer months Johnson toured nationally and internationally as a Dancer with Sun Ra and His Arkestra, performing in such places as Nigeria, Italy, France, and the Netherlands. As a choreographer, he crafted dance numbers for local productions such as the musical Liberty Avenue, and Off-Broadway Plays including Who Loves the Dancer by Rob Penny and How do you Spell Watergait by James Durrah. He continued to pursue local stage work and made his film debut in the John Russo horror film Midnight. Johnson would also go on to direct theater, notably the first staged production of August Wilson’s Jitney in 1982. 
</note>
  <note>The Ford E. and Harriet R. Curtis Theatre Collection of Pittsburgh Performing Arts Information Files, CTC.Infofiles.Pgh, Curtis Theatre Collection, Archives &amp; Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh Library System</note>
  <subject authority="Local Sources">
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart>Dunham, Katherine</namePart>
    </name>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="Local Sources">
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart>Johnson, Robert</namePart>
    </name>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="Local Sources">
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart>Johnson, Stephanie</namePart>
    </name>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="Local Sources">
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart>Penny, Rob</namePart>
    </name>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="Local Sources">
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart>Wilson, August</namePart>
    </name>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="Local Sources">
    <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>University of Pittsburgh. Department of Black Community Education, Research and Development</namePart>
    </name>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="Local Sources">
    <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>University of Pittsburgh. Kuntu Repertory Theatre</namePart>
    </name>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <topic>African American dance</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <topic>African American dance -- History -- 20th century</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <topic>Black Arts movement</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <topic>Choreographers -- United States</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <topic>Dance -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <topic>Dance -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- United States</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <topic>Modern dance -- United States -- History -- 20th century</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <topic>Performing arts -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh</topic>
  </subject>
  <location>
    <physicalLocation>ULS Archives &amp; Special Collections</physicalLocation>
  </location>
  <recordInfo>
    <descriptionStandard>dacs</descriptionStandard>
    <recordContentSource authority="marcorg"/>
    <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">170920</recordCreationDate>
    <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
  </recordInfo>
  <identifier type="pitt">US-PPiU-ctc201403</identifier>
  <name>
    <namePart>University of Pittsburgh</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text">depositor</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
</mods>
