<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>W. Stephen Coleman Papers, 1981-2011</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <name type="personal" usage="primary">
    <namePart>Coleman, W. Stephen</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text">creator.</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <typeOfResource collection="yes" manuscript="yes">mixed material</typeOfResource>
  <genre authority="rdacontent">text</genre>
  <genre authority="aat">Personal papers</genre>
  <genre authority="lcgft">Finding aids.</genre>
  <originInfo>
    <place>
      <placeTerm type="code" authority="marccountry">pau</placeTerm>
    </place>
    <dateOther>1981-2011</dateOther>
    <dateIssued encoding="marc" point="start">1981</dateIssued>
    <dateIssued encoding="marc" point="end">2011</dateIssued>
    <issuance>monographic</issuance>
  </originInfo>
  <language>
    <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
  </language>
  <physicalDescription>
    <extent unit="linear feet (14 boxes)">18.0</extent>
    <form type="media" authority="rdamedia">unmediated</form>
    <form type="carrier" authority="rdacarrier">other</form>
    <note type="arrangement">Organized into three series: I. Three Rivers Shakespeare Festival, 1983-1999. II. Pitt Repertory Theatre, 1981-2009. III. Acting and Directing, 1981-2011. Chronological arrangement.</note>
  </physicalDescription>
  <abstract type="Summary">This collection contains the promptbooks, scripts, and production notes of W. Stephen Coleman (1943-).  Dr. Coleman served as a faculty director and professor in the Theatre Arts department at the University of Pittsburgh (1981-2011) and a resident director for the Three Rivers Shakespeare Festival (1983-1992).  This collection details both acting and directing projects while in residence in the Pittsburgh area. It also includes materials for professional and non-professional acting engagements and directing projects undertaken by Coleman during his Pittsburgh years.  Production materials contain rehearsal and director notes, press materials, set and costume designs, and miscellaneous administrative materials. Promptbooks, Production Materials, and Recordings in various formats (audio and VHS video) comprise the bulk of the collection.  The collection is arranged in three series:  Three Rivers Shakespeare Festival, University of Pittsburgh Repertory Theatre, and Acting and Directing.</abstract>
  <accessCondition type="restriction on access">No restrictions.</accessCondition>
  <accessCondition type="use and reproduction">The University of Pittsburgh holds the property rights to the material in this collection, but the copyright may still be held by the original creator/author. Researchers are therefore advised to follow the regulations set forth in the U.S. Copyright Code when publishing, quoting, or reproducing material from this collection without the consent of the creator/author or that go beyond what is allowed by fair use.</accessCondition>
  <note>Processing Information: This collection was processed by Colleen Reilly in January 2006.  Additional materials were processed and added to the collection by William Daw in 2015.</note>
  <note type="preferred citation">W. Stephen Coleman Papers, 1981-2011, CTC.2011.01, Curtis Theatre Collection, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh</note>
  <note type="acquisition">Original donation; Gift; W. Stephen Coleman; 201104.</note>
  <note type="acquisition">Additional materials; Gift; W. Stephen Coleman; 201510.</note>
  <note type="biographical/historical">W. Stephen Coleman, Associate Professor and Director of Undergraduate Studies at the University of Pittsburgh, received his Bachelor's and Master's degrees from the University of Oklahoma in the mid 1960's, and his Doctorate from the University of Utah in 1973. As a specialist in Shakespeare in performance and the performance areas of actor-training and directing, he joined the undergraduate and graduate faculty of the University of Pittsburgh in 1981 as head of the then newly created MFA Actor Training Program, a post he held until 1990. Between 1992 and 1999, he served as Chair of the Department of Theatre Arts. He taught at several other universities and colleges, including the University of Texas at Austin, the London International Film School, Carnegie Mellon University, the University of Utah, the University of Oklahoma, and the Oklahoma College of Liberal Arts. He was awarded tenure at Pitt in 1986.  Dr. Coleman continued to work professionally, dividing his time between acting (under the name "Alex Coleman") and directing.  While it was a mainstay of Pitt's theatrical scene, Dr. Coleman appeared in over a dozen major roles with the Three Rivers Shakespeare Festival. He has performed with the New York Shakespeare Festival, the National Shakespeare Company, the Montana Repertory Theatre, and several other regional theatres. He is a long-time member of Actors' Equity Association, the Screen Actors Guild, and the American Federation of Television and Radio Artists.  In addition to over 200 roles on the stage, he has played featured roles in a number of films and TV movies, made-for-television movies, and many others. He has performed in hundreds of radio and television commercials, and has appeared in numerous industrial films.  Coleman was a prolific director.  He directed the world premiere of Daniel Frezza's adaptation of Oscar Wilde's The Picture of Dorian Gray (2000) for the Pittsburgh Irish and Classical Theatre.  He served as a faculty director for Pitt Repertory Theatre (1982- ) and in 1996 staged a highly acclaimed Hamlet and Rosencrantz and Guildenstern are Dead in repertory.  Between 1983 and 1992 he served as one of two Resident Directors for the Three Rivers Shakespeare Festival (TRSF). His directorial efforts for both TRSF and the University were consistently cited as among the "Top Ten" in Pittsburgh from 1983-2006.  He directed for numerous professional theatres in the Pittsburgh region, including the theatre at Hartwood Acres, (Sleuth and One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest).  He also staged the world premiere of Pennsylvania State Poet Samuel Hazo's Until I'm Not Here Anymore and directed the video adaptation of this work that aired on Public Television.  In addition to his theatrical activities, Dr. Coleman staged readings for the Center for Creative Non-Fiction at the University of Pittsburgh. He was a regular presenter of lectures and workshops on performance subjects related to acting, directing, Shakespearean production, and the development of theatre skills that can be used in the courtroom. During his tenure at the University of Texas at Austin, he was the Founder and Artistic Director of the Gallimaufry Players, producing and directing four summers' worth of free Shakespeare-In-The-Park.</note>
  <note>Pittsburgh Irish and Classical Theatre Records, 1997-2015, CTC.2009.02, ; Curtis Theatre Collection, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh.</note>
  <note>Three Rivers Shakespeare Festival Records, 1980-1995, CTC.1995.01, ; Curtis Theatre Collection, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh.</note>
  <note>University of Pittsburgh Theatre Arts Department Records, 1960-1986, CTC.1974.02, ; Curtis Theatre Collection, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh.</note>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart>Coleman, W. Stephen</namePart>
    </name>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <name type="personal">
      <namePart>Shakespeare, William</namePart>
      <namePart type="date">1564-1616</namePart>
    </name>
    <topic>Stage history</topic>
    <geographic>Pennsylvania</geographic>
    <geographic>Pittsburgh</geographic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Pittsburgh Irish &amp; Classical Theatre.</namePart>
    </name>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>Pittsburgh Public Theater.</namePart>
    </name>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <name type="corporate">
      <namePart>University of Pittsburgh.</namePart>
      <namePart>Department of Speech and Theatre Arts.</namePart>
    </name>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <name type="conference">
      <namePart>Three Rivers Shakespeare Festival (Pittsburgh, Pa.)</namePart>
    </name>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <topic>College theater</topic>
    <geographic>Pennsylvania</geographic>
    <geographic>Pittsburgh</geographic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="local">
    <topic>Faculty papers</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh">
    <topic>Performing arts</topic>
    <geographic>Pennsylvania</geographic>
    <geographic>Pittsburgh</geographic>
  </subject>
  <name>
    <namePart>University of Pittsburgh</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text">depositor</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <location>
    <physicalLocation>University of Pittsburgh</physicalLocation>
  </location>
  <identifier type="oclc">ocn966446196</identifier>
  <relatedItem>
    <location>
      <url displayLabel="Finding aid">http://digital.library.pitt.edu/cgi-bin/f/findaid/findaid-idx?type=simple;c=ascead;view=text;subview=outline;didno=US-PPiU-ctc201101</url>
    </location>
  </relatedItem>
  <recordInfo>
    <descriptionStandard>dacs</descriptionStandard>
    <recordContentSource authority="marcorg">PIT</recordContentSource>
    <recordCreationDate encoding="marc">161220</recordCreationDate>
    <recordChangeDate encoding="iso8601">20170105143233.0</recordChangeDate>
    <recordIdentifier>8653278</recordIdentifier>
    <recordOrigin>Converted from MARCXML to MODS version 3.5 using MARC21slim2MODS3-5.xsl
				(Revision 1.106 2014/12/19)</recordOrigin>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm authority="iso639-2b" type="code">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
  </recordInfo>
<identifier type="pitt">US-PPiU-ctc201101</identifier></mods>
