<mods:mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:copyrightMD="http://www.cdlib.org/inside/diglib/copyrightMD" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd http://www.cdlib.org/inside/diglib/copyrightMD http://www.cdlib.org/groups/rmg/docs/copyrightMD.xsd">
  <mods:originInfo>
    <mods:dateCreated keyDate="yes" encoding="iso8601">1976-09-06</mods:dateCreated>
    <mods:dateOther type="sort">1976-09-06T00:00:00</mods:dateOther>
  </mods:originInfo>
  <mods:accessCondition>
    <copyrightMD:copyright copyright.status="copyrighted" publication.status="unknown">
      <copyrightMD:rights.holder>
        <copyrightMD:name>United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America</copyrightMD:name>
      </copyrightMD:rights.holder>
    </copyrightMD:copyright>
  </mods:accessCondition>
  <mods:relatedItem displayLabel="source" type="host">
    <mods:titleInfo>
      <mods:title>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</mods:title>
    </mods:titleInfo>
    <mods:note type="prefercite">Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13), United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America Collection, 1935-2006, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh</mods:note>
  </mods:relatedItem>
  <mods:abstract>This cartoon describes the effects the Brownell bill had on unions and their reactions to the bill. Caption 1:  Even while there was growing recognition that Sen. Joe McCarthy was a menace to the country, President Eisenhower's Attorney-General Herbert Brownell pushed for a bill to require government licensing of labor unions. This, in effect, would give Washington the power to decree which unions workers could join. The bill had the enthusiastic support of employers. It was backed by conservative legislators as well as by some with liberal reputations including Hubert Humphrey.  Caption 2:  Among trade unions there was widespread opposition to the Brownell bill. The Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen called it "Hitlerism." Both the AFL and the CIO, not yet merged, opposed the bill and the Amalgamated Clothing Workers saw the bill as "weapons of a police state." Despite this, the bill was passed by Congress and signed by Eisenhower. Laying the groundwork for the enforcement of the new law, employers were firing union members who fought government control.  Caption 3:  The General Electric Co. fired some 20 workers, members of UE, the IUE and AFL craft unions who had incurred the enmity of the various congressional anti-labor committees including Sen. McCarthy's. Among those who lost their jobs were John Nelson, president of Local 506, Erie, Pa. The UE charged that the firings were the result of a conspiracy between the company and McCarthy in violation of workers' constitutional rights and the union contract. UE News, Vol. XXXVIII, Issue No. 17</mods:abstract>
  <mods:typeOfResource>still image</mods:typeOfResource>
  <mods:physicalDescription>
    <mods:form>Comic strips</mods:form>
    <mods:extent/>
  </mods:physicalDescription>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>University of Pittsburgh</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">depositor</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>James Lerner</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">contributor</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:genre>Publication plate</mods:genre>
  <mods:titleInfo>
    <mods:title>Labor History - 151: Law to License Unions</mods:title>
  </mods:titleInfo>
  <mods:identifier type="pitt">ue13.3.1.151</mods:identifier>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>Fred Wright</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">creator</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:subject authority="local">
    <mods:topic>Politics and Legislation</mods:topic>
  </mods:subject>
</mods:mods>