<mods:mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:copyrightMD="http://www.cdlib.org/inside/diglib/copyrightMD" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd http://www.cdlib.org/inside/diglib/copyrightMD http://www.cdlib.org/groups/rmg/docs/copyrightMD.xsd">
  <mods:originInfo>
    <mods:dateCreated keyDate="yes" encoding="iso8601">1974-05-06</mods:dateCreated>
    <mods:dateOther type="sort">1974-05-06T00:00:00</mods:dateOther>
  </mods:originInfo>
  <mods:accessCondition>
    <copyrightMD:copyright copyright.status="copyrighted" publication.status="unknown">
      <copyrightMD:rights.holder>
        <copyrightMD:name>United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America</copyrightMD:name>
      </copyrightMD:rights.holder>
    </copyrightMD:copyright>
  </mods:accessCondition>
  <mods:relatedItem displayLabel="source" type="host">
    <mods:titleInfo>
      <mods:title>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</mods:title>
    </mods:titleInfo>
    <mods:note type="prefercite">Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13), United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America Collection, 1935-2006, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh</mods:note>
  </mods:relatedItem>
  <mods:abstract>This cartoon depicts the victory of the maritime strikers who gained control over their own union and encouraged hundreds of thousands of others to seek union protection, although the AFL continued to refuse to organize the large majority of workers. Caption 1:  Three days after the San Francisco general strike had started in protest against assaults on the maritime strikers, the AFL central body voted to end it, 191 to 174. But the police and National Guard attacks on the maritime strikers had come to an end. And when negotiations were over the longshoremen had won a 6-hour day, 30-hour week, time and a half for overtime as well as the end of the notorious shape-up.  Caption 2:  Now they had the hiring hall run by the union. This marked an end to the racketeering and the gangsterism with which the officials of the Intl. Longshoremen's Assn. had long maintained control over the waterfront. The Intl. Seamen's Union was recognized as spokesman for the seamen. In this strike there rose a new waterfront leader, Harry Bridges, who was elected head of the ILA local and then president of the West Coast District.  Caption 3:  The West Coast strike was a big step towards the coming national organizing drive. Hundreds of thousands were seeking union protection. But the AFL kept its doors closed, admitted some into federal local unions which were bureaucratic dues collection agencies and insisted on ignoring the mass production industries. Although 35 million were eligible for unions, AFL and independents had only a little over 3 1/2 million members. UE News, Volume XXXVI, Issue No. 9</mods:abstract>
  <mods:typeOfResource>still image</mods:typeOfResource>
  <mods:physicalDescription>
    <mods:form>Comic strips</mods:form>
    <mods:extent/>
  </mods:physicalDescription>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>University of Pittsburgh</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">depositor</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>James Lerner</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">contributor</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:genre>Publication plate</mods:genre>
  <mods:titleInfo>
    <mods:title>Labor History - 99: Waterfront Strike Won</mods:title>
  </mods:titleInfo>
  <mods:identifier type="pitt">ue13.3.1.099</mods:identifier>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>Fred Wright</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">creator</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:subject authority="local">
    <mods:topic>Union Organization</mods:topic>
  </mods:subject>
</mods:mods>