<mods:mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:copyrightMD="http://www.cdlib.org/inside/diglib/copyrightMD" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd http://www.cdlib.org/inside/diglib/copyrightMD http://www.cdlib.org/groups/rmg/docs/copyrightMD.xsd">
  <mods:originInfo>
    <mods:dateCreated keyDate="yes" encoding="iso8601">1976-06-21</mods:dateCreated>
    <mods:dateOther type="sort">1976-06-21T00:00:00</mods:dateOther>
  </mods:originInfo>
  <mods:accessCondition>
    <copyrightMD:copyright copyright.status="copyrighted" publication.status="unknown">
      <copyrightMD:rights.holder>
        <copyrightMD:name>United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America</copyrightMD:name>
      </copyrightMD:rights.holder>
    </copyrightMD:copyright>
  </mods:accessCondition>
  <mods:relatedItem displayLabel="source" type="host">
    <mods:titleInfo>
      <mods:title>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</mods:title>
    </mods:titleInfo>
    <mods:note type="prefercite">Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13), United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America Collection, 1935-2006, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh</mods:note>
  </mods:relatedItem>
  <mods:abstract>This cartoon describes the Taft-Hartley Act's effects on the labor movement during the 1950's. Caption 1:  The Taft-Hartley law having weakened unions, it became possible for the government to impose a wage freeze on workers in the early 1950's with the Korean war as the excuse. Negotiated vacations, holidays and wage increases were either cut out of thousands of agreements or radically reduced by the Wage Stabilization Board despite rising prices. Employers were reaping the economic benefits of the anti-labor law and the attacks on civil liberties.  Caption 2:  To further weaken labor's ability to resist employers, Sen. Robert Taft, co-sponsor of the law, prodded the Justice Dept. to prosecute labor leaders for not being in compliance with that law. When some government, officials protested that they didn't have the evidence to get convictions, the Ohio Republican replied: "They may not be able to pin it on them, but they can catch some of them with a jury."  Caption 3:  In 1953, freshman Arizona Sen. Barry Goldwater proposed a bill requiring unions to be federally licensed. The terms of this proposed legislation were so harsh that a spokesman for the American Federation of Labor said that any union that ever proposed anything the Communist Party advocated,  including income taxes and public schools, could be put out of business. He and other labor spokesmen saw the bill as resembling what was done to labor in Germany by Adolph Hitler. UE News, Vol. XXXVIII, Issue No. 12</mods:abstract>
  <mods:typeOfResource>still image</mods:typeOfResource>
  <mods:physicalDescription>
    <mods:form>Comic strips</mods:form>
    <mods:extent/>
  </mods:physicalDescription>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>University of Pittsburgh</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">depositor</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>James Lerner</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">contributor</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:genre>Publication plate</mods:genre>
  <mods:titleInfo>
    <mods:title>Labor History - 147: Labor pays for repression</mods:title>
  </mods:titleInfo>
  <mods:identifier type="pitt">ue13.3.1.147</mods:identifier>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>Fred Wright</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">creator</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:subject authority="local">
    <mods:topic>Politics and Legislation</mods:topic>
  </mods:subject>
</mods:mods>