<mods:mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:copyrightMD="http://www.cdlib.org/inside/diglib/copyrightMD" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd http://www.cdlib.org/inside/diglib/copyrightMD http://www.cdlib.org/groups/rmg/docs/copyrightMD.xsd">
  <mods:originInfo>
    <mods:dateCreated keyDate="yes" encoding="iso8601">1976-11-08</mods:dateCreated>
    <mods:dateOther type="sort">1976-11-08T00:00:00</mods:dateOther>
  </mods:originInfo>
  <mods:accessCondition>
    <copyrightMD:copyright copyright.status="copyrighted" publication.status="unknown">
      <copyrightMD:rights.holder>
        <copyrightMD:name>United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America</copyrightMD:name>
      </copyrightMD:rights.holder>
    </copyrightMD:copyright>
  </mods:accessCondition>
  <mods:relatedItem displayLabel="source" type="host">
    <mods:titleInfo>
      <mods:title>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</mods:title>
    </mods:titleInfo>
    <mods:note type="prefercite">Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13), United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America Collection, 1935-2006, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh</mods:note>
  </mods:relatedItem>
  <mods:abstract>This cartoon depicts continued successes of organizations fighting repression of the McCarthy era.  However, repressive policies still continued. Caption 1:  Other victories were being won in the fight against repression. The American Newspaper Guild rejected a convention proposal that it for the first time adopt political qualifications for membership. The large New York local of the American Federation of Television and Radio Artists condemned the widespread industry blacklist. Congress defeated an attempt to put a loyalty oath into the federal housing law which would have barred members of over 300 organizations from such housing.  Caption 2:  The government's fifth attempt to deprive Harry Bridges, president of the Intl. Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union, of his citizenship on charges that he was a communist was thrown out by a federal judge in 1955. Still, the government continued to push its repressive policies. Eisenhower's Atty.-Gen. Brownell started proceedings to outlaw the Mine, Mill and Smelter Workers Union while it was leading a strike of 30,000 copper corporation employees.  Caption 3:  The attorney-general also procured an indictment against the United Auto Workers for its support of Democrats in the 1954 election. State committees were also in the act, one of the worst operating in Massachusetts on behalf of GE and other corporations. UE Pres. Fitzgerald told this committee: "The day will come when we look back on this period with as much shame as we now look back on the Salem witch-hunts and the Sacco-Vanzetti case." UE News, Vol. XXXVIII, Issue No. 21</mods:abstract>
  <mods:typeOfResource>still image</mods:typeOfResource>
  <mods:physicalDescription>
    <mods:form>Comic strips</mods:form>
    <mods:extent/>
  </mods:physicalDescription>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>University of Pittsburgh</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">depositor</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>James Lerner</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">contributor</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:genre>Publication plate</mods:genre>
  <mods:titleInfo>
    <mods:title>Labor History - 154: Victories Over Repression</mods:title>
  </mods:titleInfo>
  <mods:identifier type="pitt">ue13.3.1.154</mods:identifier>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>Fred Wright</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">creator</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:subject authority="local">
    <mods:topic>Red Scare, Politics and Legislation</mods:topic>
  </mods:subject>
</mods:mods>