<mods:mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:copyrightMD="http://www.cdlib.org/inside/diglib/copyrightMD" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd http://www.cdlib.org/inside/diglib/copyrightMD http://www.cdlib.org/groups/rmg/docs/copyrightMD.xsd">
  <mods:originInfo>
    <mods:dateCreated keyDate="yes" encoding="iso8601">1972-04-03</mods:dateCreated>
    <mods:dateOther type="sort">1972-04-03T00:00:00</mods:dateOther>
  </mods:originInfo>
  <mods:accessCondition>
    <copyrightMD:copyright copyright.status="copyrighted" publication.status="unknown">
      <copyrightMD:rights.holder>
        <copyrightMD:name>United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America</copyrightMD:name>
      </copyrightMD:rights.holder>
    </copyrightMD:copyright>
  </mods:accessCondition>
  <mods:relatedItem displayLabel="source" type="host">
    <mods:titleInfo>
      <mods:title>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</mods:title>
    </mods:titleInfo>
    <mods:note type="prefercite">Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13), United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America Collection, 1935-2006, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh</mods:note>
  </mods:relatedItem>
  <mods:abstract>This cartoon depicts the strike of steelworkers in Homestead, Pa.  The workers were locked out of the factory after they rejected company demands, and soon the company was advertising for scabs. Caption 1:  The demand for the 8-hour day in 1890 was so popular among working people that unions experienced very rapid growth. In four months the Carpenters Union added 132 new locals. And it won its demand. As a result of the May 1st strikes that year, hundreds of thousands of workers across the country had their hours reduced. AFL Pres. Gompers wrote that with this movement labor had won new "courage and hope."  Caption 2:  Two years later, labor was up against a major attack from some of the biggest employers. Officials of the Carnegie Steel Co. informed employees at the Homestead, Pa., works that at the expiration of the contract with the Amalgamated Assn. of Iron and Steel Workers, the union would no longer be recognized and wages cut by a 22 percent average. The workers rejected the company demands but sought further negotiations.  Caption 3:  Instead, they soon found themselves locked out. Although the union had been limited to the skilled workers, all 3,800, including those who had not been permitted to join, voted to fight the company. The workers put a steam launch onto the river to watch for scabs. The company began advertising for scabs as far away as Boston, St. Louis and Philadelphia. It arranged for 300 Pinkerton guards to run in scabs. UE News, Vol. XXXIV, Issue No. 7</mods:abstract>
  <mods:typeOfResource>still image</mods:typeOfResource>
  <mods:physicalDescription>
    <mods:form>Comic strips</mods:form>
    <mods:extent/>
  </mods:physicalDescription>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>University of Pittsburgh</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">depositor</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>James Lerner</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">contributor</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:genre>Publication plate</mods:genre>
  <mods:titleInfo>
    <mods:title>Labor History - 50: Homestead Strike I</mods:title>
  </mods:titleInfo>
  <mods:identifier type="pitt">ue13.3.1.050</mods:identifier>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>Fred Wright</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">creator</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:subject authority="local">
    <mods:topic>Strikes, Scabs</mods:topic>
  </mods:subject>
</mods:mods>