<mods:mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:copyrightMD="http://www.cdlib.org/inside/diglib/copyrightMD" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd http://www.cdlib.org/inside/diglib/copyrightMD http://www.cdlib.org/groups/rmg/docs/copyrightMD.xsd">
  <mods:originInfo>
    <mods:dateCreated keyDate="yes" encoding="iso8601">1976-04-19</mods:dateCreated>
    <mods:dateOther type="sort">1976-04-19T00:00:00</mods:dateOther>
  </mods:originInfo>
  <mods:accessCondition>
    <copyrightMD:copyright copyright.status="copyrighted" publication.status="unknown">
      <copyrightMD:rights.holder>
        <copyrightMD:name>United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America</copyrightMD:name>
      </copyrightMD:rights.holder>
    </copyrightMD:copyright>
  </mods:accessCondition>
  <mods:relatedItem displayLabel="source" type="host">
    <mods:titleInfo>
      <mods:title>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</mods:title>
    </mods:titleInfo>
    <mods:note type="prefercite">Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13), United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America Collection, 1935-2006, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh</mods:note>
  </mods:relatedItem>
  <mods:abstract>This cartoon describes the difficulties that the UE went through in 1946, including pressures from the CIO creating rival unions to UE. Caption 1:  With the loss of a million members in 10 unions, an act of self-destruction by the leaders of the CIO, that organization was doomed as an effective representative of American workers. Prodded by the cold-war politicians, encouraged by the employers, those leaders diverted their dwindling resources to efforts to destroy the ousted unions, even helping to set up rival unions, such as the IUE, with employer assistance.  Caption 2:  Workers in the electrical manufacturing industry were special targets of this cannibalistic drive because UE had become, in a short 10 years, a most successful spokesman for the economic and political rights of working people. Within a few years, these workers, who in 1946 had the power to humble the most powerful corporations, were reduced to accepting crumbs from those same corporations. The General Electric Co. boasted of its role in this development.  Caption 3:  Taking the offensive, GE hired Lemuel Boulware to conduct the campaign for eliminating unionism as an effective force. The company would present the various unions with a set of contract proposals, permit only some minor adjustments while waging a nationwide struggle to discourage and demoralize the employees. Boulwarism became  a pattern for labor relations far beyond the electrical industry. UE News, Vol. XXXVIII, Issue No. 8</mods:abstract>
  <mods:typeOfResource>still image</mods:typeOfResource>
  <mods:physicalDescription>
    <mods:form>Comic strips</mods:form>
    <mods:extent/>
  </mods:physicalDescription>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>University of Pittsburgh</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">depositor</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>James Lerner</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">contributor</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:genre>Publication plate</mods:genre>
  <mods:titleInfo>
    <mods:title>Labor History - 143: Boulwarism, Not Bargaining</mods:title>
  </mods:titleInfo>
  <mods:identifier type="pitt">ue13.3.1.143</mods:identifier>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>Fred Wright</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">creator</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:subject authority="local">
    <mods:topic>Union Organization</mods:topic>
  </mods:subject>
</mods:mods>