<mods:mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:copyrightMD="http://www.cdlib.org/inside/diglib/copyrightMD" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd http://www.cdlib.org/inside/diglib/copyrightMD http://www.cdlib.org/groups/rmg/docs/copyrightMD.xsd">
  <mods:originInfo>
    <mods:dateCreated keyDate="yes" encoding="iso8601">1974-09-09</mods:dateCreated>
    <mods:dateOther type="sort">1974-09-09T00:00:00</mods:dateOther>
  </mods:originInfo>
  <mods:accessCondition>
    <copyrightMD:copyright copyright.status="copyrighted" publication.status="unknown">
      <copyrightMD:rights.holder>
        <copyrightMD:name>United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America</copyrightMD:name>
      </copyrightMD:rights.holder>
    </copyrightMD:copyright>
  </mods:accessCondition>
  <mods:relatedItem displayLabel="source" type="host">
    <mods:titleInfo>
      <mods:title>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</mods:title>
    </mods:titleInfo>
    <mods:note type="prefercite">Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13), United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America Collection, 1935-2006, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh</mods:note>
  </mods:relatedItem>
  <mods:abstract>The first cartoon in the Sit-Down In Auto Plants series. This cartoon depicts a strike against General Motors in 1936. Caption 1:  Earlier in 1936 the rubber workers had won their first big organizational battle at Akron, Ohio by a sit-down strike. Now, in the fall, auto workers who had had every one of their organizing efforts smashed in previous years, took hold of the sit-down tactic. Within a few months sit-down strikes against speedup and refusal to discuss grievances broke out in a number of General Motors plants. The company refused to negotiate with the union.  Caption 2:  Take up your grievance with the plant management, national GM Vice Pres. Knudsen replied in every case. On Dec. 28 the Cleveland GM workers halted production and refused to leave the plant. UAW Vice Pres. Wyndham Mortimer said they would stay there until the company agreed to meet the union nationally. Two days later the major GM plant at Flint, Mich. was stopped by a sit-down.  Caption 3:  A few days later the huge GM set-up including Atlanta, Ga., Anderson, Ind., Norwood, O., and Kansas City, were closed by the sit-down strikers. Outside the plants, particularly in Flint, the company was organizing a vigilante group to attack the strikers. Inside, the union members set up their committees to provide themselves with food, to police themselves, to organize entertainment. UE News, Vol. XXXVI, Issue No. 18</mods:abstract>
  <mods:typeOfResource>still image</mods:typeOfResource>
  <mods:physicalDescription>
    <mods:form>Comic strips</mods:form>
    <mods:extent/>
  </mods:physicalDescription>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>University of Pittsburgh</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">depositor</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>James Lerner</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">contributor</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:genre>Publication plate</mods:genre>
  <mods:titleInfo>
    <mods:title>Labor History - 108: Sit-Down In Auto Plants I</mods:title>
  </mods:titleInfo>
  <mods:identifier type="pitt">ue13.3.1.108</mods:identifier>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>Fred Wright</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">creator</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:subject authority="local">
    <mods:topic>Strikes, Businesses</mods:topic>
  </mods:subject>
</mods:mods>