<mods:mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:copyrightMD="http://www.cdlib.org/inside/diglib/copyrightMD" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd http://www.cdlib.org/inside/diglib/copyrightMD http://www.cdlib.org/groups/rmg/docs/copyrightMD.xsd">
  <mods:originInfo>
    <mods:dateCreated keyDate="yes" encoding="iso8601">1976-11-22</mods:dateCreated>
    <mods:dateOther type="sort">1976-11-22T00:00:00</mods:dateOther>
  </mods:originInfo>
  <mods:accessCondition>
    <copyrightMD:copyright copyright.status="copyrighted" publication.status="unknown">
      <copyrightMD:rights.holder>
        <copyrightMD:name>United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America</copyrightMD:name>
      </copyrightMD:rights.holder>
    </copyrightMD:copyright>
  </mods:accessCondition>
  <mods:relatedItem displayLabel="source" type="host">
    <mods:titleInfo>
      <mods:title>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</mods:title>
    </mods:titleInfo>
    <mods:note type="prefercite">Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13), United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America Collection, 1935-2006, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh</mods:note>
  </mods:relatedItem>
  <mods:abstract>This cartoon depicts the nationwide Westinghouse strike of 1955. Caption 1:  The country was in one of its periodic recessions in 1955 leading the big corporations to think that they could impose their wills on working people. Especially in the electrical manufacturing industry where employers had succeeded  in splitting the workers was this so. UE Westinghouse workers all over the country struck in October of that year after refusing to accept a five year contract which provided for a three percent increase. When IUE members at Westinghouse struck there were 60,000 out.  Caption 2:  This was the first national Westinghouse strike since UE shut this company and GE down across the country in 1946. Westinghouse applied for court injunctions against the strikers and promoted back to work movements. As this failed to bring the desired results, the company was helped in its strikebreaking efforts by Atty.-Gen. Herbert Brownell who called on the Subversive Activities Control Board to investigate the union in a move to outlaw the organization through the Brownell-Butler Law.  Caption 3:  The tie-up between this Wall Street lawyer in the Justice Dept. and big business became clearer when a Westinghouse attorney argued before the Pennsylvania unemployment compensation bureau that the strikers were not entitled to compensation because of the Brownell action. Instead of weakening the strikers, this coordinated attack won them new support. At Essington, Pa., the members of 22 unions joined the Local 107 picket line in a demonstration of labor solidarity as the strike approached its fourth month. UE News, Vol. XXXVIII, Issue No. 22</mods:abstract>
  <mods:typeOfResource>still image</mods:typeOfResource>
  <mods:physicalDescription>
    <mods:form>Comic strips</mods:form>
    <mods:extent/>
  </mods:physicalDescription>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>University of Pittsburgh</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">depositor</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>James Lerner</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">contributor</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:genre>Publication plate</mods:genre>
  <mods:titleInfo>
    <mods:title>Labor History - 155: The 1955 Westinghouse Strike</mods:title>
  </mods:titleInfo>
  <mods:identifier type="pitt">ue13.3.1.155</mods:identifier>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>Fred Wright</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">creator</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:subject authority="local">
    <mods:topic>Strikes, Economy</mods:topic>
  </mods:subject>
</mods:mods>