<mods:mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:copyrightMD="http://www.cdlib.org/inside/diglib/copyrightMD" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd http://www.cdlib.org/inside/diglib/copyrightMD http://www.cdlib.org/groups/rmg/docs/copyrightMD.xsd">
  <mods:originInfo>
    <mods:dateCreated keyDate="yes" encoding="iso8601">1973-07-23</mods:dateCreated>
    <mods:dateOther type="sort">1973-07-23T00:00:00</mods:dateOther>
  </mods:originInfo>
  <mods:accessCondition>
    <copyrightMD:copyright copyright.status="copyrighted" publication.status="unknown">
      <copyrightMD:rights.holder>
        <copyrightMD:name>United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America</copyrightMD:name>
      </copyrightMD:rights.holder>
    </copyrightMD:copyright>
  </mods:accessCondition>
  <mods:relatedItem displayLabel="source" type="host">
    <mods:titleInfo>
      <mods:title>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</mods:title>
    </mods:titleInfo>
    <mods:note type="prefercite">Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13), United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America Collection, 1935-2006, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh</mods:note>
  </mods:relatedItem>
  <mods:abstract>This cartoon shows how divided railway workers, in different craft unions,  were forced to settle separately. Their defeat hurt  the entire labor movement and people were disillusioned: Union membership dropped from 5 million to 3.5 million. Caption 1:  The most sweeping injunction in American labor history, issued against the railway shop craft strikers in 1922, said that no one could aid the strikers "by letters, telegrams, telephones, word of mouth." Attorney General Daugherty announced that the government would be used to "prevent the labor unions of the country from destroying the open shop." This denial of free speech even shocked many opponents of the strike.  Caption 2:  Their strike was up against insuperable odds of fellow unionists, employers, press and government. The 400,000 strikers had to agree to separate settlements with individual roads on as best terms as they could get. What had been done to them could be seen from the fact that 175,000 strikers were forced out of their unions and into company unions. The divided railway workers were hit so hard that the entire labor movement was hurt.  Caption 3:  During the first World War the leaders of the AFL unions had seen themselves as having gained a "partnership" with the employers and a liberal president, Woodrow Wilson. But by 1923 all these illusions had been wiped out in some of the worst battles ever forced on labor in the U.S. Total union membership dropped from 5 million to 3% million. Wages were slashed, introduction of new machinery saw over a million permanently thrown out of industrial jobs. UE News, Volume XXXV, Issue No. 15</mods:abstract>
  <mods:typeOfResource>still image</mods:typeOfResource>
  <mods:physicalDescription>
    <mods:form>Comic strips</mods:form>
    <mods:extent/>
  </mods:physicalDescription>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>University of Pittsburgh</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">depositor</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>James Lerner</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">contributor</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:genre>Publication plate</mods:genre>
  <mods:titleInfo>
    <mods:title>Labor History - 82: 1922 Railway Strike</mods:title>
  </mods:titleInfo>
  <mods:identifier type="pitt">ue13.3.1.082</mods:identifier>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>Fred Wright</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">creator</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:subject authority="local">
    <mods:topic>Union Organization, Politics and Legislation, Strikes</mods:topic>
  </mods:subject>
</mods:mods>