<mods:mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:copyrightMD="http://www.cdlib.org/inside/diglib/copyrightMD" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd http://www.cdlib.org/inside/diglib/copyrightMD http://www.cdlib.org/groups/rmg/docs/copyrightMD.xsd">
  <mods:originInfo>
    <mods:dateCreated keyDate="yes" encoding="iso8601">1971-03-08</mods:dateCreated>
    <mods:dateOther type="sort">1971-03-08T00:00:00</mods:dateOther>
  </mods:originInfo>
  <mods:accessCondition>
    <copyrightMD:copyright copyright.status="copyrighted" publication.status="unknown">
      <copyrightMD:rights.holder>
        <copyrightMD:name>United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America</copyrightMD:name>
      </copyrightMD:rights.holder>
    </copyrightMD:copyright>
  </mods:accessCondition>
  <mods:relatedItem displayLabel="source" type="host">
    <mods:titleInfo>
      <mods:title>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</mods:title>
    </mods:titleInfo>
    <mods:note type="prefercite">Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13), United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America Collection, 1935-2006, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh</mods:note>
  </mods:relatedItem>
  <mods:abstract>This cartoon depicts the corruption among employers during the Civil War which resulted in riots and strikes breaking out across the country. Caption 1:  While workers went off to war or stayed behind to support the northern troops, their employers were getting rich. The draft law enabled a man to evade service by getting a substitute or by paying $300. Only the wealthy could afford this and their sons did not have to go off to fight. Many bought a poor man to die for them. Judge Mellon, starter of the Mellon millionaires, told his son that it was "only greenhorns" who enlist.  Caption 2:  Based on runaway profiteering, prices charged the people and the government was scandalous. Many modern fortunes had their origin in those days when as one magazine wrote: "The men button their waistcoats with diamonds...and  women powder their faces with gold and silver dust." Strikes broke out all over the country as workers needed more money and unions began growing again. Between 1863 and 1864 about 300 new unions were organized.  Caption 3:  Those who opposed the northern cause used labor's grievances to promote riots against the draft. The New York recruiting office was destroyed and for three days a mob rampaged across the city wrecking railroads, street car lines, shipyards, factories and machine shops. Homes and offices of Republican leaders were wrecked. It was estimated that over 400, many Negroes, were killed and wounded and $5 million dollars property destroyed. UE News, Vol. XXXIII, Issue No. 5</mods:abstract>
  <mods:typeOfResource>still image</mods:typeOfResource>
  <mods:physicalDescription>
    <mods:form>Comic strips</mods:form>
    <mods:extent/>
  </mods:physicalDescription>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>University of Pittsburgh</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">depositor</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>James Lerner</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">contributor</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:genre>Publication plate</mods:genre>
  <mods:titleInfo>
    <mods:title>Labor History - 23: Corruption and Riots</mods:title>
  </mods:titleInfo>
  <mods:identifier type="pitt">ue13.3.1.023</mods:identifier>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>Fred Wright</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">creator</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:subject authority="local">
    <mods:topic>War, Strikes, Businesses</mods:topic>
  </mods:subject>
</mods:mods>