<mods:mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:copyrightMD="http://www.cdlib.org/inside/diglib/copyrightMD" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd http://www.cdlib.org/inside/diglib/copyrightMD http://www.cdlib.org/groups/rmg/docs/copyrightMD.xsd">
  <mods:originInfo>
    <mods:dateCreated keyDate="yes" encoding="iso8601">1972-04-17</mods:dateCreated>
    <mods:dateOther type="sort">1972-04-17T00:00:00</mods:dateOther>
  </mods:originInfo>
  <mods:accessCondition>
    <copyrightMD:copyright copyright.status="copyrighted" publication.status="unknown">
      <copyrightMD:rights.holder>
        <copyrightMD:name>United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America</copyrightMD:name>
      </copyrightMD:rights.holder>
    </copyrightMD:copyright>
  </mods:accessCondition>
  <mods:relatedItem displayLabel="source" type="host">
    <mods:titleInfo>
      <mods:title>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</mods:title>
    </mods:titleInfo>
    <mods:note type="prefercite">Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13), United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America Collection, 1935-2006, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh</mods:note>
  </mods:relatedItem>
  <mods:abstract>This cartoon depicts how the company hired 300 armed guards who went to the strike grounds so that new workers could begin to work instead of those on strike, however the strikers tried to stop them. 8,000 National Guardsmen were brought in to the mill. Caption 1:  The 300 Pinkerton guards hired to break the strike of Homestead steelworkers were armed with rifles and put on two barges towed by a steamboat down the Monongahela River, a few miles from the struck mill. The aim was to sneak them in unseen by the strikers. But this maneuver failed when the strikers got wind of it. They broke through the fence surrounding the mill.  Caption 2:  The barges they had come on were set afire. All over the country labor protested this brutal attack and the strike continued with wide support from labor. A few days later, however, Gov. Pattison answered the demand of the Carnegie Steel Co. and ordered out 8,000 National Guardsmen. His reason: "the actual communism of these people. They believe the works are theirs quite as much as Carnegie's.  Caption 3:  The armed strikebreakers started firing into the crowd and were answered in kind. The workers floated burning, oil-soaked boxes on the river. The battle of Homestead had started at 4 a.m. on July 6, 1892. It raged until 5 that afternoon. At least 9 workers were killed and three of the Pinkertons. Surrender terms were finally agreed on-the agents were to march off to a skating rink. UE News, Vol. XXXIV, Issue No. 8</mods:abstract>
  <mods:typeOfResource>still image</mods:typeOfResource>
  <mods:physicalDescription>
    <mods:form>Comic strips</mods:form>
    <mods:extent/>
  </mods:physicalDescription>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>University of Pittsburgh</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">depositor</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>James Lerner</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">contributor</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:genre>Publication plate</mods:genre>
  <mods:titleInfo>
    <mods:title>Labor History - 51: Homestead Strike II</mods:title>
  </mods:titleInfo>
  <mods:identifier type="pitt">ue13.3.1.051</mods:identifier>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>Fred Wright</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">creator</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:subject authority="local">
    <mods:topic>Strikes, Scabs</mods:topic>
  </mods:subject>
</mods:mods>