<mods:mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:copyrightMD="http://www.cdlib.org/inside/diglib/copyrightMD" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd http://www.cdlib.org/inside/diglib/copyrightMD http://www.cdlib.org/groups/rmg/docs/copyrightMD.xsd">
  <mods:originInfo>
    <mods:dateCreated keyDate="yes" encoding="iso8601">1971-11-01</mods:dateCreated>
    <mods:dateOther type="sort">1971-11-01T00:00:00</mods:dateOther>
  </mods:originInfo>
  <mods:accessCondition>
    <copyrightMD:copyright copyright.status="copyrighted" publication.status="unknown">
      <copyrightMD:rights.holder>
        <copyrightMD:name>United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America</copyrightMD:name>
      </copyrightMD:rights.holder>
    </copyrightMD:copyright>
  </mods:accessCondition>
  <mods:relatedItem displayLabel="source" type="host">
    <mods:titleInfo>
      <mods:title>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</mods:title>
    </mods:titleInfo>
    <mods:note type="prefercite">Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13), United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America Collection, 1935-2006, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh</mods:note>
  </mods:relatedItem>
  <mods:abstract>This cartoon depicts rioting that took place in Pittsburgh where the Pennsylvania Railroad had cut wages.  Many were killed or wounded after militiamen were brought in. Caption 1:  The strike of 40 firemen and brakemen on the Baltimore and Ohio sparked a nationwide rail strike which spread all the way to California. The high spot was Pittsburgh where the Pennsylvania Railroad had cut wages and ordered each crew to take out 36 cars instead of the previous 18. This would have meant the laying off of half the workers. A committee of engineers offered to accept the wage cut if promised that it would be taken back when business got better.  Caption 2:  Secretly, the Trainmen's Union, an industrial organization, was formed taking in engineers, conductors, brakemen and firemen. The workers stopped freight train movements by massing on the tracks. When Sheriff Fife read the riot act they refused to break up the massed strikers. Take back the wage cut and layoff order, the workers demanded. Delegations of businessmen and miners came to declare support.  Caption 3:  The governor brought in the Philadelphia militia which fired into a crowd, killing 20 men, women and children; 29 were wounded. A Grand Jury investigating the assault branded it "unauthorized, willful and wanton killing--murder." Thousands of workers from mills, mines, factories marched to the scene and drove the troops to seek shelter in the roundhouse where they spent the night surrounded. The troops were forced out when the roundhouse started burning. UE News, Vol. XXXIII, Issue No. 22</mods:abstract>
  <mods:typeOfResource>still image</mods:typeOfResource>
  <mods:physicalDescription>
    <mods:form>Comic strips</mods:form>
    <mods:extent/>
  </mods:physicalDescription>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>University of Pittsburgh</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">depositor</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>James Lerner</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">contributor</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:genre>Publication plate</mods:genre>
  <mods:titleInfo>
    <mods:title>Labor History - 39: Troops Attack Strikers</mods:title>
  </mods:titleInfo>
  <mods:identifier type="pitt">ue13.3.1.039</mods:identifier>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>Fred Wright</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">creator</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:subject authority="local">
    <mods:topic>Strikes</mods:topic>
  </mods:subject>
</mods:mods>