<mods:mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:copyrightMD="http://www.cdlib.org/inside/diglib/copyrightMD" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd http://www.cdlib.org/inside/diglib/copyrightMD http://www.cdlib.org/groups/rmg/docs/copyrightMD.xsd">
  <mods:originInfo>
    <mods:dateCreated keyDate="yes" encoding="iso8601">1973-09-03</mods:dateCreated>
    <mods:dateOther type="sort">1973-09-03T00:00:00</mods:dateOther>
  </mods:originInfo>
  <mods:accessCondition>
    <copyrightMD:copyright copyright.status="copyrighted" publication.status="unknown">
      <copyrightMD:rights.holder>
        <copyrightMD:name>United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America</copyrightMD:name>
      </copyrightMD:rights.holder>
    </copyrightMD:copyright>
  </mods:accessCondition>
  <mods:relatedItem displayLabel="source" type="host">
    <mods:titleInfo>
      <mods:title>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</mods:title>
    </mods:titleInfo>
    <mods:note type="prefercite">Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13), United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America Collection, 1935-2006, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh</mods:note>
  </mods:relatedItem>
  <mods:abstract>This cartoon depicts the formation of the Progressive Party after  the death of President Harding.  It ran Sen. Robert M. LaFollette for president and Sen. Burton K. Wheeler for vice. Caption 1:  The 1920's were marked by widespread attacks on unions, on foreign born and on radicals. The employers used their papers and the government agencies to label all one and the same. Behind these assaults on liberty there was proceeding the wildest orgy of speculation and corruption the country had ever seen. It reached into the White House itself where President Harding was surrounded by a gang, including cabinet members, who stole the United States blind.  Caption 2:  The president died in 1923 under what has always been regarded as suspicious circumstances. Some of his cronies including Secy. of Interior Fall went to jail for conniving with the oil companies to give them government-owned oil lands. The whole country was aware of the "Ohio Gang's" thievery. Labor and the country were taking such a beating that independent political action was widely recognized as the need of the day. Vice Pres. Coolidge succeeded Harding.  Caption 3:  When the democrats in 1924 nominated Wall Street lawyer John W. Davis and the Republicans the inept Calvin Coolidge, whose claim to fame was that he had broken the Boston policemen's strike, a Progressive Party was formed. It ran Wisconsin Sen. Robert M. LaFollette (who had opposed entry in the first World War) for president and Montana Sen. Burton K. Wheeler for vice president. These men were known as enemies of the trusts. UE News, Volume XXXV, Issue No. 18</mods:abstract>
  <mods:typeOfResource>still image</mods:typeOfResource>
  <mods:physicalDescription>
    <mods:form>Comic strips</mods:form>
    <mods:extent/>
  </mods:physicalDescription>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>University of Pittsburgh</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">depositor</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>James Lerner</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">contributor</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:genre>Publication plate</mods:genre>
  <mods:titleInfo>
    <mods:title>Labor History - 85: The Harding Era</mods:title>
  </mods:titleInfo>
  <mods:identifier type="pitt">ue13.3.1.085</mods:identifier>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>Fred Wright</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">creator</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:subject authority="local">
    <mods:topic>Politics and Legislation</mods:topic>
  </mods:subject>
</mods:mods>