<mods:mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:copyrightMD="http://www.cdlib.org/inside/diglib/copyrightMD" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd http://www.cdlib.org/inside/diglib/copyrightMD http://www.cdlib.org/groups/rmg/docs/copyrightMD.xsd">
  <mods:originInfo>
    <mods:dateCreated keyDate="yes" encoding="iso8601">1972-12-25</mods:dateCreated>
    <mods:dateOther type="sort">1972-12-25T00:00:00</mods:dateOther>
  </mods:originInfo>
  <mods:accessCondition>
    <copyrightMD:copyright copyright.status="copyrighted" publication.status="unknown">
      <copyrightMD:rights.holder>
        <copyrightMD:name>United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America</copyrightMD:name>
      </copyrightMD:rights.holder>
    </copyrightMD:copyright>
  </mods:accessCondition>
  <mods:relatedItem displayLabel="source" type="host">
    <mods:titleInfo>
      <mods:title>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</mods:title>
    </mods:titleInfo>
    <mods:note type="prefercite">Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13), United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America Collection, 1935-2006, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh</mods:note>
  </mods:relatedItem>
  <mods:abstract>This cartoon illustrates how violent businesses were willing to get to break strike; a woman was killed and workers' families were beaten and clubbed. Caption 1:  Although the Lawrence, Mass. textile strikers in 1912 were accused in the press of planting dynamite it was soon proved that agents of the American Woolen Co. had done the planting in order to discredit the strikers. The company president was arrested. When troops (martial law had been declared) killed a woman picket, strike leaders Ettor and Giovannitti were arrested as "accessories to murder."  Caption 2:  IWW leader Bill Haywood took over leadership of the strike. To lessen the burden of starvation facing the strikers, it was decided to send several hundred children to other communities to be taken care of in the homes of sympathizers. One group left and then as a second  trainload was about to go, the police attacked the line of mothers and children, clubbed them, and dragged them to a military truck.  Caption 3:  The few union members in the mills belonged to the AFL Textile Workers and about 1,000 to the IWW. A spontaneous walkout against the wage cut flared up. And the IWW undertook to turn this into a disciplined strike against the wage cut. Two of its leaders, Joseph E. Ettor and Arturo Giovannitti, came to help. The press accused the strikers of being dynamiters. Police fired on the pickets and killed a woman. UE News, Volume XXXIV, Issue No. 26</mods:abstract>
  <mods:typeOfResource>still image</mods:typeOfResource>
  <mods:physicalDescription>
    <mods:form>Comic strips</mods:form>
    <mods:extent/>
  </mods:physicalDescription>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>University of Pittsburgh</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">depositor</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>James Lerner</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">contributor</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:genre>Publication plate</mods:genre>
  <mods:titleInfo>
    <mods:title>Labor History - 67: Lawrence Strike</mods:title>
  </mods:titleInfo>
  <mods:identifier type="pitt">ue13.3.1.067</mods:identifier>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>Fred Wright</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">creator</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:subject authority="local">
    <mods:topic>Strikes</mods:topic>
  </mods:subject>
</mods:mods>