<mods:mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:copyrightMD="http://www.cdlib.org/inside/diglib/copyrightMD" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd http://www.cdlib.org/inside/diglib/copyrightMD http://www.cdlib.org/groups/rmg/docs/copyrightMD.xsd">
  <mods:originInfo>
    <mods:dateCreated keyDate="yes" encoding="iso8601">1977-02-22</mods:dateCreated>
    <mods:dateOther type="sort">1977-02-22T00:00:00</mods:dateOther>
  </mods:originInfo>
  <mods:accessCondition>
    <copyrightMD:copyright copyright.status="copyrighted" publication.status="unknown">
      <copyrightMD:rights.holder>
        <copyrightMD:name>United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America</copyrightMD:name>
      </copyrightMD:rights.holder>
    </copyrightMD:copyright>
  </mods:accessCondition>
  <mods:relatedItem displayLabel="source" type="host">
    <mods:titleInfo>
      <mods:title>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</mods:title>
    </mods:titleInfo>
    <mods:note type="prefercite">Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13), United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America Collection, 1935-2006, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh</mods:note>
  </mods:relatedItem>
  <mods:abstract>This cartoon describes the UE's campaign during the depression of 1958-59 to urge the government to take action against rampant unemployment. Caption 1:  One of the periodic depressions that characterize the nation's economy hit working people in 1958-59. As unemployment soared to almost 5 million, according to official figures, the UE called for government and corporate actions to provide jobs. Of the General Electric and Westinghouse companies, the union demanded the introduction of a 37.5 hour work week at 40 hours pay with a further cut to 35 hours a year later.  Caption 2:  During the year past, about 40,000 employees had been laid off at General Electric, so severe was this depression. Profit statements by these and other corporations revealed that profits soared along with unemployment. UE wrote all unions holding contracts with the two companies urging them to also make a shorter work week a leading issue in their negotiations. None of them did. The companies rejected the demand.  Caption 3:  The union organized a nationwide campaign among its members and in their communities for governmental action against unemployment. The union's program called for tax cuts for workers, extension of unemployment compensation for longer periods, and for a massive public works program. A UE lobby brought delegates from all over the country to Washington. As a result, Congress took steps to extend unemployment compensation. UE News, Vol. XXXIX, Issue No. 4</mods:abstract>
  <mods:typeOfResource>still image</mods:typeOfResource>
  <mods:physicalDescription>
    <mods:form>Comic strips</mods:form>
    <mods:extent/>
  </mods:physicalDescription>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>University of Pittsburgh</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">depositor</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>James Lerner</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">contributor</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:genre>Publication plate</mods:genre>
  <mods:titleInfo>
    <mods:title>Labor History - 161: Anti-Depression Program</mods:title>
  </mods:titleInfo>
  <mods:identifier type="pitt">ue13.3.1.161</mods:identifier>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>Fred Wright</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">creator</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:subject authority="local">
    <mods:topic>Economy, Politics and Legislation</mods:topic>
  </mods:subject>
</mods:mods>