<mods:mods xmlns:mods="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:copyrightMD="http://www.cdlib.org/inside/diglib/copyrightMD" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-4.xsd http://www.cdlib.org/inside/diglib/copyrightMD http://www.cdlib.org/groups/rmg/docs/copyrightMD.xsd">
  <mods:originInfo>
    <mods:dateCreated keyDate="yes" encoding="iso8601">1975-06-16</mods:dateCreated>
    <mods:dateOther type="sort">1975-06-16T00:00:00</mods:dateOther>
  </mods:originInfo>
  <mods:accessCondition>
    <copyrightMD:copyright copyright.status="copyrighted" publication.status="unknown">
      <copyrightMD:rights.holder>
        <copyrightMD:name>United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America</copyrightMD:name>
      </copyrightMD:rights.holder>
    </copyrightMD:copyright>
  </mods:accessCondition>
  <mods:relatedItem displayLabel="source" type="host">
    <mods:titleInfo>
      <mods:title>Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13)</mods:title>
    </mods:titleInfo>
    <mods:note type="prefercite">Labor History Series (Series 13.3.1), Fred Wright Publication Plates (Subgroup 13.3), Fred Wright Papers (UE.13), United Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers of America Collection, 1935-2006, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh</mods:note>
  </mods:relatedItem>
  <mods:abstract>This cartoon depicts American labor's support in World War II. Caption 1:  Built on the principle that all workers, regardless of race, creed, sex or political belief were to be organized, the unions of the CIO continued to make sweeping organizational gains. The UE, for example, in 1941 was able to renew its national contract with GE, negotiate the first national agreement with Westinghouse, add 116,000 members to its ranks and win wage increases estimated at over $63 million. The UE's organizational campaigns and contract negotiations were coordinated with other CIO unions.  Caption 2:  But the drive for world conquest which impelled Adolph Hitler was, at the same time, entering its final stages. After helping Gen. Franco destroy the Spanish republic, the German fascist leader invaded country after country in Europe and launched aerial warfare against Britain in an attempt to soften that country up for invasion. In the summer of 1941, the German armies attacked the Soviet Union. Six months later, Japan, Germany and Italy declared war on the United States.  Caption 3:  With the Soviet armies offering strong resistance in the east, Britain holding up Nazi invasion plans in the west and the United States building up its might for eventual full scale participation in the fight against fascist aggression, American labor pledged full strength to victory. President Franklin D. Roosevelt named a CIO-AFL Victory Board of eight to advise him which included representatives of the major unions of the AFL and CIO, among them UE Secy.-Treas. Julius Emspak. UE News, Vol. XXXVII, Issue No. 12</mods:abstract>
  <mods:typeOfResource>still image</mods:typeOfResource>
  <mods:physicalDescription>
    <mods:form>Comic strips</mods:form>
    <mods:extent/>
  </mods:physicalDescription>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>University of Pittsburgh</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">depositor</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>James Lerner</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">contributor</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:genre>Publication plate</mods:genre>
  <mods:titleInfo>
    <mods:title>Labor History - 127: War Engulfs the United States</mods:title>
  </mods:titleInfo>
  <mods:identifier type="pitt">ue13.3.1.127</mods:identifier>
  <mods:name>
    <mods:namePart>Fred Wright</mods:namePart>
    <mods:role>
      <mods:roleTerm type="text">creator</mods:roleTerm>
    </mods:role>
  </mods:name>
  <mods:subject authority="local">
    <mods:topic>War</mods:topic>
  </mods:subject>
</mods:mods>